This meeting is being recorded.
There's 77 of you. Well,
74ish.
So, it's good for me to go through some
announcements.
If you guys have questions, raise your
hand. Tag Rob in the chat.
get them answered before we start class.
So things I have
in my notes to announce
really nothing new but
signup sheet for groups has been around
for a while. Uh, a lot of you have
groups. I went through last night at
I guess at Eastern it would have been
like 1 or 2 o'clock. And so if your name
was in around then then you do have a
group. And
as of today I did check and if your name
was in around that time last night then
the group leader has reached out to you.
I've told the group leaders they only
have to reach out once with Facebook
Messenger and that's it. If you failed
to read the directions where it says use
your Facebook profile name, then you're
kind of out of luck cuz uh it's not
their job to,
as somebody would say, hunt down Red
October. I mean, it's right in there.
Um, next,
if you're going to use the signup sheet,
read the directions. Says, "Put your
name at the bottom. Don't delete my
notes." I can see the edit history, too.
That's
ridiculous.
Next,
group chat. Group chat will no longer be
for any extended troubleshooting.
particularly related to GCP.
Um Rob and I might have an install
session for people that still don't have
installs. I'm not sure really how many
people have left to do that. Uh even
that stuff at this point is going to
start to be cut down cuz everyone's been
in there for a long time. Unless someone
somehow gets added to the group chat,
which at this point I don't know how
they would really, but that's up to
Theo. I might make an exception for
them. But besides that, you guys have
had plenty of time.
Uh,
next, well, installs was already stated,
but yeah, today in class, there should
be absolutely no questions on making
your GCP account, setting up G-Cloud if
that gets used, installing VS Code, uh,
stuff like that. Because if you're in
here right now, that means that you're
in Zion, which means you had your
deliverables done. If you're in here and
you don't have those done, I'm really
curious how you got the Zoom link.
Uh, let's see. That goes into sharing
stuff. Nobody better be sharing the Zoom
links. Don't share anything in Zion in
the group chat or vice versa. Don't
share the passcode even with people in
your in your study group. It's pinned in
the chat for a reason. Everyone is
there. They can get it. I don't want it
being shared with other people. You
shouldn't want to do that. Makes you
liable for getting in trouble.
None of that's fun. Um, finally,
I hope you guys took the opportunity
this week to prepare for class. I laid
out notes, laid out prep material for
the networking
stuff and gave you the Udemy
recommendations. If it I I would be
definitely looking for the GCP
masterclass Udemy for it to be on sale
if you don't have it now. Um you
definitely wait for it to be on sale,
but that's the first Udemy you should be
getting if you don't want to get them
all at one time. Um, and you should
definitely be making progress in that.
Like at this point, the group leaders
will set their own pace with the m with
that material. Um, they'll probably set
random homework as class progresses, but
you should be taking some initiative.
Uh, and like I did mention in the group
chat, there are several labs that don't
work right in that nobody asked me
questions.
So, I I'm just going to assume nobody
really has done the labs in there.
Anyh who, any questions?
So based upon that um if you look at
really okay um I made a new uh page in
the repo and this is the homework page.
You go
and I have uh the homework that was
going to be necessary for this class and
you you'll have to we'll have to do it
next week and you just have to I tell
you what what demies they are and what
sections you have to go through. So,
it's just two demis, one section per
demi. It's not that bad. They're both
focusing on on PPC. Uh, it shouldn't
shouldn't be that hard for you to deal
with. Should actually be pretty.
>> And just to clarify, since markdown is
new to you, uh, apparently. So, this
goes to this Udemy. This goes to this
Udemy.
>> I don't know why it did three. I just
did this. So, I pressed enter. I didn't
see a three on there. I didn't think
there was
>> Click code real quick. I'll show you why
it's wrong.
>> See? No, I Yeah, I understand what it
did.
>> Uh the It's the empty line and Well, you
put three right there. Actually, that
too. That'll
>> No, I didn't put the three. I didn't do
it. It did automatically.
>> Okay.
>> I swear I did not do that.
>> I believe I'm going to have to go back
over there and edit it. But yeah, this
is again section. This is all of it. all
of it. So, um the reason I put all of it
in because people like really do all of
it like yes, what what part of section
do you not understand?
>> So, Rob,
>> uh sorry, Rob, check the Facebook
Messenger chat.
>> Sure.
>> See here.
Uh, your recorder. Um, try it again,
Julian. I'm here right now.
>> Okay.
>> Your TIQS [ __ ] strippers.
Ah,
I like that.
>> Big deal.
>> What?
>> First off, happy birthday.
>> Thank you.
>> How are you doing?
>> Doing well. Actually,
>> this is the first time I've had
>> Happy birthday.
>> What is it? I had a therapist involved
with a birthday.
Like involved front and center.
>> Birthday.
>> So,
are you going to do this correctly?
Okay.
So, yeah.
>> Thank you. Thank you guys. I haven't
said thank you to everybody on Facebook
yet, but yes, thank you. So yeah, my my
it's it's been a pretty good birthday.
>> Happy birthday.
>> Thank you.
>> Happy happy happy birthday. Bless up on
your earth from my youth.
>> And
amazing Ukrainian girls from my past did
a massive amount of Hello Bigheads to me
today.
Happy birthday big head.
>> Yep. Happy birthday Theo. No reachback
gang man.
Okay, that's my that's the first thing.
So, hope you had a good day.
Get down to some business. Did you give
Richie a link to Zion?
>> No.
>> Okay.
>> I'm very
>> Oh, it's Rob. You didn't change the
privacy setting, did you?
>> No, I did not. But
>> this is this is why we have security
gates. This good. The pipeline's working
as as expected,
so it's fine.
Okay, that's all I had. Can carry on.
>> I'll rent you. I'll look at him real
quick. I'm
>> I'm sure Rob handled it.
>> There's There's no
no.
>> You saw what I said about that in the in
the chat.
>> Yeah.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. So, I I know you got to deal with
it. He's fine where he is right now.
>> I thought you I thought Denil would deal
with it.
>> Oh, then I'll deal with it.
>> Denil is not you.
>> Oh, Denil. Oh, what? No.
>> The AI have it.
>> That's That's different. That's
the Neil is very nice, civilized. I'm
not
I I'm more of an animal. He's actually
refined human, although he's a robot.
He's more human than than I am. More
humane.
>> If you're saying a human's more more If
you're saying a robot's more human than
you, then I am uh very worried.
>> But that's that's Did you see
Bladeunner?
>> Ryan Gosling. Yeah. No, no, the first
one
>> did not
>> the whole that was the whole thing of
that was to show what humanity is. And I
watched it. I I told people I failed
that movie the first time because the
nonhuman showed me he was more human
than I was and I was stunned. But then I
watched second time, I passed the second
time. It's actually a test on your
humanity. So again, a robot being more
human than me, it actually makes sense.
>> Yes. Uh
>> yeah. And what Apple did to the found
dude, don't get me started. Like the
foundation. Oh, so Chad GPT and I had a
lot of conversation about Apple
Foundation, how it sucks.
He's like like
should come back from the grave and burn
Apple down.
It's just so horrible. I can't believe
they did it. Oh,
in this economy. Yeah, it's so it it's I
can't even watch it anymore. Like, oh,
the the mule is, you know, needs a W
minute, but then [ __ ] The mule set
systems on fire. Multiple. My goodness.
He was he was a real competent villain.
Anyway, I got the Jack. I got the N. All
right, so let me go look at this.
Thanks, guys. Oh my goodness, you have
so many of these things. I can't even
recognize them. Okay, so again, thank
you for uh the birthday warnings. Sorry,
birthday wishes. Um I had a pretty good
day. Um, as some of you guys might know,
or I said it last night, um, my company
originally gave me offer uh to work in
support with Brazil and Japan and the
Japan office came back with a counter
offer to take me straight to Japan.
And so I accepted it, but it's verbal
and um we have to go through the details
and the the the devil is really in the
details that it's a really big detail
thing. So we're trying to figure out
how this can actually work for me to go
back to Japan.
I just want to say that that offer is
there. Um, I'm kind of
wanting to do it. Like, this would be
great. Kind of not. Um, I'm kind of like
I do kind of wanted to go to Columbia or
Brazil and make the gym. So, if I went
to Japan, there's no way I can make the
gym. The gym would stay in storage. And
I'm kind of like I would prefer just to
go make the gym and set everything up,
right? Um, it's not only lack of space,
the cost. I can't do it. I would need to
pay one year of um, rent up front. I am
not doing that. Literally, no. It's it
literally, it's impossible. I could not
do that.
So, anyway, um, I have to take it out of
my my trust fund. I'm not doing that.
Some stupid stuff. Uh, Rio, no, no, I'm
um I'm responsible. I don't want to get
a STD and get shot. So, no. No, Rio.
It's not that's not gonna happen.
Anyway, guys, uh glad to see you guys
all here. We got 102 of you. Raw is law.
No, no. Raw is do dead. Dead. I don't
want dead. I I'll just I I I
if I go to Brazil, it's got to be FIPA.
That's the the main city that I like.
So, it's going to be there. Yeah.
Anyway, um so this is your um homework.
I uh every week from now on, I'll be
putting your homework over to here so
you know what the expectations are.
Especially if I do demies. Um this week,
you need to be having your um like this
week's kind of the introduction to demi.
You do need to get your demis. Get them
on sale. They're always going to be on
sale at some point. Um Easter is next
week, so there's going to be an Easter
sale. For the love of God, do not pay
full price for your demi. Okay? Do not.
If you pay full price for your demi, you
are cuckoo. Do not do that. So, I click
on here.
Okay. Here is the demi right here. Right
now is $14.99. That's pretty good price.
All right. It's not $94.
And I tell you what section. Hold on. I
tell you what section you're supposed to
go to. Where is my Wait, where is my
repo? Where did my repo go? It's back
there. Oh, there it is. Okay, so it tell
you what section to go to. I say all of
it because I don't want to hear any
things like I don't want to do all do I
have to do everything? Yes, you have to
do everything. It's not hard to do.
Okay, so go ahead and do that. Um, next
week um part of your homework will be
course will be Terraform and there'll be
the Terraform book. So, um,
Aaron has put the Terraform,
uh, instructions, the book instructions
someplace, I'm sure, in your
documentation. Please go look at the
Terraform book as well.
>> Not not for the book yet, but I I can
fine. Okay. So, we're gonna have fun
with uh VPC today.
Okay.
Uh, Levarius, you have time. We're not
doing this now. I want you to focus on
this now cuz we got to we got to do VPC
in here uh correctly. Okay.
I was wondering I was getting I was
starting to get build. I was like what
the heck's going on? I had a VPC
running. No, I had a I had a VM running.
So
>> yeah, a V a VPC by itself and GCP
shouldn't cost you anything. They don't
charge like AWS for the the gateways and
stuff.
>> Yeah, that's I know that is true. done
with that one. Okay. Um
so,
uh let's go ahead and go up to here.
VPC. We're going to deal with VPC today.
And um why it's used in the cloud. We'll
go over here say VPC the top. This says
here VPC networks. Go ahead and click on
that.
Okay. Now, we have here VPC. All right.
Now, this is important thing. I need you
to understand. Okay, this is this is
kind of big. All right, so it's a big
thing to know. Now, when we start when
we last week when we did our our
lessons, uh we were using the default
VPC. Now, a VPC, what is it? Is a
virtual private cloud. It's a virtual
network that is inside your cloud
environment or your cloud project and
it's where you actually have networking
established. Um most networking in the
cloud is flat. Uh if particularly if you
compare it to Cisco networking or data
centers networking the s the
networking inside the inside the cloud
is extremely flat. So you still need to
know about it. You still need to know
how it works. Okay. So if I click on
here you see if I see here default.
Okay.
And I look on here and I see subnets.
Right. All right. So, this is where I
need to do a little bit of your of your
um need to introduce some concepts to
you because GCP is a little bit
different from AWS. All right. So, in
AWS, every region has the same um
default network subnet.
All right. In GCP, this is not true.
All of this the networks are different
but they're all listed together.
So essentially
all of GCP
is under what we call a 10net
and this is kind of an amazing thing.
Like the way they did it is actually
kind of smart. It's at least a little
bit intelligent. All right. So I need to
I need to start teaching you guys
subnitting now and understanding
networking so that you can actually
understand what's going on here. And
there's a lot of concepts that you need
to understand. Now what I'm going to
show you is the RFC for this. You need
to understand this RFC. If you do not
understand this RFC, you are shooting
yourself in the foot. And when you go
into interviews, they can legitimately
ask you this RFC information. And if you
can't answer, it's a legitimate reason
to not hire you. So, I'm putting I'm put
spending some time with you on this.
Make sure you understand what this RFC
is. This RFC is RFC 1918.
Say RFC
1918.
Okay.
And there we go. Here we go.
Okay. RFC 1918.
Expand this a little bit.
All right. So, put a one in the chat.
And this is the first time you've ever
heard about RFC 1918.
Never heard about this. What the hell
you're talking about, The
Okay.
Yep.
Yeah. You need to bookmark this. TIQS
says yes and that you need to memorize
this thing to tell you the truth. Put a
two in the chat if you heard about this
from the AWS course or another GCP
course but you not entirely familiar
with it.
Okay.
So, I'm going to tell you guys this and
particularly you guys in class who said
put a two in here.
You cannot go to an interview and do
cloud for cloud engineering and not know
1918.
If you don't understand this, you are in
true jeopardy of losing the job.
I'm serious.
You have to know this. And I say you
need to know this RFC forwards and
backwards.
In fact, shoot. I'm going to give I'm
going to start making tests for this
thing. Um because if you don't know
this, I don't I do not know how you can
do cloud engineering. It's not going to
be possible because you can't set you
can't stand up infrastructure without
it. All right? So, you need to
understand this. This isn't something
you play around with. This isn't a game.
This is absolutely necessary. If you
second guess and say, "Well, I don't
know. Maybe Theo's wrong." Go to
CompTIA.
You're not set for six figures. I'm
straight out be honest with you. It's
not something you play around with. You
take this deadly seriously. Now, if you
guys come from a Cisco point of view,
you know straight out, you don't know
this RFC. You cannot work in Cisco. It's
dead. You're done. It's over. There's no
way you could do sustain without this.
So in the cloud, this is still
necessary. Although it's not as it's
mission critical, but it's not like
yeah, we're not even looking at your
resume. Okay. So this is talking about
uh resource allocation or IP uh
allocations
to uh your network um to private to
private networks and to public networks.
So we need to understand what is the
difference between a public network and
a private network.
A public network is a network which is
routable on the internet and the
internet is public.
A private network is not routable on the
internet. It is only routable in a
private premises.
for example, your house.
So, I'm going to give you an example
right now.
We'll go over here.
Okay, hold on.
Here's my little
my little git bash. Can you guys see the
screens? Can you see my git bash? Oh,
sorry. Can you see? Yeah. See my git
bash? Yes. No. See it? Okay. Now I'm
gonna say if config.
>> Wait, really?
>> IP
>> Windows,
>> but it's still okay. Anyway,
>> it doesn't alias it and get bash.
>> All right. So, you notice right here I
have Let's go see if I can get this a
little bit bigger. There we go. I have
an IP address for my machine of 1921
16886.230.
230.
This is inside my house. Okay. And has a
default gateway of 192 168 86.1.
That 86.1
is my default router. So this is how you
read this. Your network is here. I'm
going to tell you how to do this. Okay.
Your network is here. This is your
network value, your first three octets
and then the IP address for your actual
machine is the last octet. So this is
what we call these are octets. One
octet, two octet, three octet, four
octets.
All right. So for my machine my my local
my Mac my Windows machine I have right
here its IP address actually is230
and the network is 192 168.86.
Okay.
Now if you know subnetting real quick
maybe we'll spend a little bit of time
subnetting. You know this is easy to
tell because of the subnet mask. This
subnet mask tells you real quick that
the first three octets are to be used
for networking and the last octet is to
be used for hosts.
Okay? And I'm going to teach this
process to you, but this is how you read
this. Now, if you guys look at this, you
will notice on this RFC
1918,
it has this private IP address of 1921
168.0. zero. This is reserved
for private networks. And look, I have
right Yeah, I have it right here. 192
168. This is reserved for private
network. That's inside my house. So, all
of you at home, you either have a 10et
address, a 172 address, or 192 address.
All of you have it. There's no
exceptions.
The only way this would be exceptional
is if you were working in a data center
right now and okay if you if you're if
you're working in a data center you can
be a little cheeky and say I've got
something else which you know most
likely you do but if you're at home like
for most of us
this is what you got. Okay. So how many
of you have a 10 net? Put a one in the
chat if you got a 10net as your private
IP address. A 10 net is any of them
here. That's why I say this is a when I
say a 10 net that means your network
begins with 10.
Okay. How many you guys got a 10?
Okay. How many of you have a 172 net?
Put a put a two in the chat if you got a
172.
Yeah, there you go.
Okay, for the rest of you, put a three
in the chat if you have a 192.
Yeah, I thought the majority of you
going to have a 10. Oh, I have a 192.
Okay,
if you got a 10 net, yeah, your ISP is
kind of smoking something, but you could
do it. Just it's not smartest thing to
do for a whole network. 192 is 192.168
is the best one. Shout out to
Shouldn't be that way, but it can work.
Okay. All right.
So, okay. So, right now we've
established that all of us have a
network that is based on these IP
addresses. Okay, this is very very very
important. Okay. Okay. So you guys all
know these are private IP addresses.
These are private IP addresses that
you're using in your home or you're
using in the office. Okay. Either one,
it doesn't matter. These IP addresses
are not routable to the internet.
Okay.
Yeah. Yeah. your your um Oh, but see
it's still a slash24, right? Yeah,
that's okay. So, Erin, yeah, that's
>> subnet mask is 24 bits. Yeah, I didn't
even notice this is I didn't set up this
networking equipment though. My
brother-in-law did. I don't know.
>> Your brother-in-law is using the default
values of either your ISP or their
hardware. And he's obviously not a
network engineer because if you do this
and you keep this default like this is a
this is a default value that the
Russians know about so they can just do
attack on it. Um yeah
he's not as smart as you are. You're
you're doing
>> uh he's he's as smart more he's more
intelligent but he's a software engineer
very much.
I can I can just use chat to do this
job. That's fine. Okay. Uh Theo, don't
be so bad. Don't be Well, let's Okay.
Kaya, you are loving Theo. Loving loving
new Theo. Loving. Okay. All right.
No, we need software engineers. They're
They are wonderful people. We need them.
We need them to do software. Without it,
we can't have all these nice
applications. Okay, there we go. Okay.
So, when you go back over to here, you
will notice that all of these networks
in GCP are all 10 nets.
Okay, these are all 10 nets. It's just
the way. Okay, see all of them are 10
bits. I say for the purposes of the
class, you should use um
I think for GCP, you should use uh
192. you might as well just use 192 168
because we're not going to do anything
that complicated. We might do something
a little complicated, but for the most
part, you just use 192 168. You can do
most of it, most of your networking.
So, this is what you got to first you
got to do is plan things out. All right.
So,
here I'm going to go back to go to Iowa
real quick. Um, if we go Where's Iowa?
Uh, US East US Central one, right? So,
this is Iowa, right? Oh, just so you
know, Iowa is about to face the wrath of
the Ali tomorrow. And Elite 8. Mhm.
I'm going to teach those.
See, in Poland, they make Iowa jokes.
So, we're going to teach them what? I
teach them a lesson.
Okay. So um this one here has that has a
basic network. Let's expand this. Okay,
everybody can see it, right? We good?
That has a basic network of 10
128 to 0020.
Okay, first off, okay, if you know
anything about network engineering, I
don't want to spend too much time on
this, but
a AWS does this also. They use a
slash20.
A slash20 is really lazy.
It's really unprofessional. I don't know
why they use a slash20.
Okay, so let get my note notepad out
real quick.
Uh, notepad.
Go.
Okay.
Is there a new one?
Not this one. Not this one.
No, I want a new one. New. Okay. There
we go. Okay.
So,
what you need to do first is plan out
how you're going to actually do this.
Now, in AWS, this is much more
complicated because you have a lot more
subnets to deal with. What I say is
first 198
168.x.0
zero.
>> Well, we'll make try to make this
bigger. There we go. That's going to be
your default network. And then you got
to try to think what other kind of
networks you're going to need. You might
need other subnets inside of your
network for later on, but this will just
be your base in the beginning. So, I
know in AWS we do this in a much more
complicated matter. It's because there's
a lot more going on in AWS. In GCP, it's
a lot easier to be honest. It's a lot
more basic. So all we're going to do in
this case is I'm going to say my network
is going
my main network
is going to be 192.16810.0
and the slash we're going to use our
subnet mask it's going to be a /24.
This is going to be able to solve most
of our issues that we have. I'm going to
go and keep it like that. Now you guys,
right? You see, see I have an X here,
right? You guys don't have to use 10.
You could use another number. This is
what I say to you. Don't use zero.
Don't use 192 1680.0.
Don't do that.
you can do it
like technically don't because it's an
easily attackable uh network. It's
almost a default value and people will
assume that you're already using it.
Also, don't use one,
okay?
Because a lot of companies use one. So,
I use zero and one. So that's where the
attacks are going to go towards.
Instead, what I want you to do is use 10
or another number. That's fine. Okay.
All right.
Before I continue,
does anybody have any questions on this?
Can ask question? I don't mind. Please
ask a question.
All right. Um, Roy,
>> greetings. How?
>> Yeah,
>> go ahead.
>> So, that screen that you have, that
screen you have on your um
computer, how did you get there?
I mean,
>> are you I don't I don't I'm I'm going to
say I got here via my keyboard and
mouse.
>> The um I I think you looked at the V VPC
networks if I'm not mistaken. Is that Is
that
>> Yeah, the VP Oh, so how do Okay, how did
I get to this in
>> Yeah,
>> in GCP.
All I do is go to the top of the search
and I type in VPC
and as you can see networks right there.
Okay. And then see how it says subnets
right down here.
>> Okay.
>> Click on it.
>> What the hell?
>> There it go. That's default. And then
subnets. Okay. There we go.
>> Thank you.
>> Uh Leland.
>> Yeah, I'm a little lost on the
connection between um this primary IPv4
range uh that you were telling us about
that started with 10 and then I know you
said the 192 which is like similar to
the IP address I saw on my MAC. How are
we Are you saying that we should be
changing
the
>> You should be making your own
>> making our own default.
>> Okay. So this one we go to network
details.
>> This name is default.
>> You got to back up a bit. Dio
are you describing? So, in essence, are
you describing to them how they're going
to architect their own private network
in a cloud?
>> Yeah. Um, you guys are going to make
making your own networks in the cloud
and you're not going to be using the
default network. I don't want you using
the default network because it's not
professional.
If you use the default network, you're
in trouble because it means you don't
know what you're doing.
All right. And also in something that a
hacker could actually anticipate. So I
want you guys to look on here real
quick. If I go to default right here and
I go to subnetss,
your Africa South one, what is your
primary IP range here?
Is it the same as this one?
>> Yes. No. Yes, it is.
>> Okay.
>> It is.
>> So, East Asia one, is it the same as
this?
>> Yeah.
>> The value is the same.
>> They all match.
>> What What is your East Asia 1?
>> 0.0.
>> It's the same.
>> Okay. East Asia 2. Is it the same?
10.170.
>> Yes, sir. Same.
Is it the same? Yes or no? I got over 50
people in here. I should get some
answers.
>> Yes, sir. Yes, sir. It's the Yes, sir.
It's the same.
>> All right. So, if it's the same, that
means the hackers in Russia also know
what these values are. And if they're
able to compromise their network, they
would know where to go.
That's the issue. If it's the same, you
don't want to use the same. You want to
use different so that they don't know
where to go. This is security concept.
That's it. You don't want to make it
easy. This what we call security and
depth. You make you always make a a new
one. You always make it your own uh
network. Uh Leland, where you go?
>> Yeah. I just want to make sure I
understand what you're saying. So when
you say they're the same, cuz I see like
140 is different from 170 and the second
three numbers. You're you're
specifically referring to the 0.0/20.
No, all I need to have if you say Africa
South one and if it's one if it's 10.218
that's the same. So if yours is the same
network as mine, they know your network
range.
So if they have if they are able to get
access to your account, they can just
run a scanner on your 10net
and if they can if they can anticipate
the the default values that you have and
if you have assets in here, then they
can take out your assets.
Okay? So the only thing I look for is
these two one the first octet and the
second octet. If they're the same as my
region as your region, we have an issue.
Okay? that. So you're not going to use
those. Okay, those are cute. So we're
going to do is we're going to create our
own VPC,
right? How do we create our own VPC?
See here, VPC networks. See this button
right here? Create VPC network. Look
good. Let's press it. Create.
And now let's let's put something here.
So birthday Birthday
hyphens allow. Okay. EPC
lowerase, guys. Lower case. Lower case.
No capitals. Description
is
I'm at the club. Okay, there we go. So,
it says set MTU automatically. That's
fine. Just keep that marbled. Subnet
creation mode custom. Okay.
And then
uh I'm going to go here and say create a
new subnet name and it's going to call
it corny.
Okay.
Copy your description there. And I'm
going to put this in Iowa. Okay. So
Iowa. Here it is. US Central one. Okay.
Oh, that's right. It has to be
lowercase.
Okay. Now, you can name it anything you
want. I don't care. Just make sure it it
agrees with your naming convention. I
don't care.
Name it what you want. And also, you can
put it in any region that you want. I
don't care.
Own it. I'm just using Iowa because Iowa
is so easy to use. That's it. And now
when we go for other classes, I'm going
to start putting my architecture in
Ireland or Sao Paulo, Tokyo, something
like that. But for now, I'm just using.
Okay. I can't believe they're going
they're part of the lead bastards.
Go kill them.
I also can't believe my ali
they had the game right down the road
for me.
Anyway,
>> Theo, did you click on configure network
profile too?
>> No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Think about
>> all I did was name, description,
didn't touch anything else. New subnet
here. Boom. Boom. Everything else is
default. Don't need to touch it.
>> Okay,
>> don't overdo it.
Okay.
Now, we need to we need to associate we
need to have an IP range. Go back to my
notepad.
I want to do this one.
Okay. Copy it.
Maybe put it right there. Paste.
I like this one. I'm not going to use a
secondary IP range. We'll do that later
on. But now, no. Okay. Private Google
access. Uh,
no. Don't. No. I don't need this.
Uh oh. On. Yep. Yep. That's right. Flow
logs on.
No, hold on. Let's turn them off. And
hybrids subnets.
No, no, no. Okay, that's fine. So,
that's all the subnet that I'm going to
need for right now.
>> Okay. Now, we need to do
>> Go ahead.
You go back up to the IP4 range.
There it is.
>> You want them copying your range, Theo?
>> Yeah, fine. You can copy my range. I I
say you should own your It doesn't need
to be 10,
but just make sure it's it's a range
that you like. Now, there's other guys
who are taking my other classes with me
before. They might use different ranges.
That's fine. I don't care if you use
different ranges. All I care is is that
it works and you're you're happy with it
and you're owning it. You're just
starting out. You're using my range. Go
for it.
>> Ow.
Lower back.
Anyway,
>> got you got you got to give the tortoise
a break.
>> I got mine was invalid.
>> You got to give the No, nothing.
Nothing. You you just you probably too
hard on your birthday. That's fine.
>> Oh, hold on, hold on, hold on. Somebody
said that
>> somebody said that it was invalid. Who
said your network range was invalid?
>> Uh, DeAndre.
>> Okay, DeAndre, put your the network
range that you want to put, put it into
the chat so I can see it.
Oh, I want Illinois to spank Duke
and then I want them to teach u Arizona
a lesson.
>> That's not going to happen.
>> Oh, whoa, whoa.
>> Yeah, that DeAndre, that'll work.
He's masked at 24 bits. So he What's
Wait, what is he? Oh, you're using 192.
Okay. Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> 192s. He's doing the same one I'm doing.
>> I don't I'm not watching the screen.
>> Well, that's okay. Uh DeAndre, uh share
your screen real quick. I got to I got
to make sure uh that I I need I need
everybody to be participating. And if
you're not getting it done right now, I
need you to speak. If this is mission
critical, you have to get it done.
>> Give me one second. That I think I
copied the whole thing, even the word.
So, I'm going have to take that out. I
think it's about to work now. Uh,
>> did you copy the word?
>> When I did a copy, I think I went
through a whole the whole line. So, now
it seemed like it works. Give me one
second. Yeah, it's working out. I copied
the whole thing instead of the number.
>> Okay. Okay.
Okay, good.
Xavier, please. Xavier, no. No,
no, no. Please.
Okay. All right. Okay. Did everybody do
this for this new subnet?
Everyone, please. Did you do it?
>> Yes.
>> If it doesn't,
>> there's not enough. I'm not getting
enough.
>> I want a screenshot
>> for your birthday.
>> For my birthday.
Give me a screenshot for my birthday. I
want a screenshot. I want to see that
you're doing it right. Christopher, no.
No. Christopher, no. See that? I have
the 1921 16810.
Pro/24.
That's a big difference. If you have
11.24,
that's a that's a host. That's one
machine.
Screen.
I want to see your screen, dude. On the
screen.
Okay. Good. Kevin. Good.
And Kevin Wil. Let's see. Kevin Wilcox,
what you got?
Kevin Wilcox, you didn't put the IP
address in there. I I don't see it. Turn
me on. I like I like the name of your
network, though.
>> Um I I'll send I'll resend it.
>> Daniel, good.
Okay,
Dominic.
Good. Dominic. Good.
Leland.
Good. Leland, where's your brother?
>> Here.
>> Both of you are here.
>> I can't always.
>> Okay. So, as long as you guys are both
here, that's good. I didn't I didn't see
your brother. I've been looking for him.
Uh Jonathan.
Good. Okay.
Trey,
good
as are all copying me. That's fine.
>> 37. No, I wanted to all be different.
>> You did.
>> No, I
didn't give them. I didn't Well, we're
going fast.
We explained this in so much more detail
in AWS.
74. Good. Good, Jack.
Good or good, Logan.
Couchy. Ouchie. Ow.
Ow. Yeah. Good. Couchy. Good. Ouch.
>> You
>> really You really got way way off that
deal.
>> What am I on? 60. Really? Okay, Everett.
Fine. You're right. Good. Savior. Good.
Xavier. Good. Mr. Kate.
Okay. Good.
Cloud.
Week after birthday PPC. It's good.
Lavarius. Good. Michael.
Good.
Wait. What did you do? Michael. Okay.
Good. Yeah. Yeah, that's right. Go.
Good. Valkyrie project. I'll take it.
Rio
private
uh private Google access. I said yes. I
said yes to there. Uh Rio,
change change that from uh off to on
Ernst.
Yep.
Good. Remember guys, here private Google
access has to be on
uh Martz.
Good.
Hey, Jock. Good.
Lonnie, what you got, Lonnie?
Okay, Lonnie, you're kind of a nerd
there. I saw the name of that. Mhm. Oh,
Taco D.
Okay, good. Bacus. Good.
Michael Dale
W. Are you serious? Well, that was
clever.
Okay, I like that. I want to see what
you do with that. That's That's clever
some.
Okay, good. Yeah, when I see that,
Michael, I'm like, he's probably going
to get a job. Okay, Mr. Gray.
Mr. Gray, you didn't give me an IP
address.
Carlton?
Really? Really? Carlton?
Yeah,
you're you're having too much fun. Trey
Bradshaw,
I'm not waiting. I'm just going to do it
now. Wait a Trey. What? What the heck?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. What? Oh,
no. That's Subway.
Yeah, you made it. Okay, fine.
Take two. Will Kevin Wilcox.
Please people, for the love of God,
change your GCP appearance to dark mode.
Please, my eyes. My eyes. Why are you
doing that to my eyes? Why
are you trying to do a denial service
attack against my eyes? Do you want to
blind me?
You too. Um, Hickley, you didn't put
your IP address in there in the
screenshot.
Okay, hold on. Let me Let's see.
There we go. Matthew Miles, thank you,
Matthew. Thank you for not blinding me.
Good job.
Make sure your private Google access is
on.
Uh Kevin Till,
okay, good. Ouch. My back. Ow.
Why is it hurting so much? Oh my god.
She really did a number on you, huh?
>> No, it was my squat press.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Your squat press. I'm I'm
sure you want to squat. So, you
squatting something. That's for sure.
>> Big booty Latinas just in increments.
>> AD
Bailey. Good job. Da y'all.
No big booty Latinas here
in Oh, yeah. You sent them home.
Ouch. Ow. Oh, nest egg. Good. Hold on.
No, Josh. Good. Nest egg.
Oh, nest egg. Private Google access
needs to be on. You have it off.
Mr. Alex K. No, no, no, no. Where
everyone? Mr. Alex K.
Good.
Kelly Moore.
Good. Kelly Moore, make sure your
private
Google access is on.
Mr. Gray,
good. Make sure private again. Make sure
your private Google access is on.
Royston.
Oh yeah. Yeah, you did it. Oh, that's
good.
Oh, you actually made a host, didn't it?
That's a top four. Wait, how the heck?
Yeah. Wait, what?
Okay. All right.
Alexander Felder.
Good.
Albert Hicks.
Good. Oh, good. Good. Good. Albert, my
back. Thomas,
baby one. I like it. Good. I need to
make a baby. I'm just going to Sixth
Street and just get busy. Okay, good.
William, good.
No, I can't do that. Can't do. No, I'm
abroad. What did you
uh Williams Stewart, you don't you
didn't give me the IP addresses. You
give me the firewall rules. We're not
there. We're not done yet.
Brandon, now sorry. Let's need to get
rid of that. Brandon,
good.
Uh Brandon, just make your private make
sure your private Google access is on.
Kevin Tate,
good. Same for you,
Charalei.
Is it still cold up there? I know
Minneapolis is cold. At least your
region is Dallas. That makes sense.
James Kent. Good. Good. Very good. Nest
egg.
Good. Okay, that's what I want. Nest
They didn't add a region. There you go.
Okay, good. Um,
Kelly, make sure that you have your
private Google access is being on.
Dwayne Johnson.
Very good.
Okay. William Stewart.
Good.
Okay.
Good. Um, make sure your private Google
access is on. Okay,
yousef.
Oh, guess that's good, you
good, good, great job.
Okay. Okay. Got for the love of God
changed it to dark mode. Okay.
Lord have mercy on my eyes. My I don't
know why.
Okay. If you want to do it with Bash
Everett, go right ahead. I can't read
what you did, but if you want to do it
that way, go ahead.
Okay, that works. Yep. John Williams,
good job. Good music, too. Okay, I know.
I know. Lavarius, people are like, "What
the hell? Why are you doing that to me?
She had a big
She has such a big booty. Should not
just be in bed sleeping right now or
have a beer? No.
No. Nothing's going on there. Uh Ted,
good.
John.
Okay. It should be okay. That's That's
good. All right.
Okay.
Gavin,
good. I need you a different region. I
like that. Brandon,
good.
Yeah, I like that.
Dominic,
good. Good. Good. Good.
Good. Now, okay.
Uh,
Kelly, more good because this case more
more is better. More is less. Let's
actually corrected.
Okay, there you go. Obriato Charles
RW. Good.
Good. Okay.
Okay. Got it. Very good. Okay.
Okay. Well,
much better. Okay. I like that skin.
Nah, Everett.
I don't know. Yeah. I want Aaron deal
with you.
Okay.
>> Well, Michael Dale, I hope somebody know
how to deal with my back. Something's
wrong. I'm having a spasm. Ah, good,
Michael Dale. Good. I like that. No,
that was Ahmad. Was that Amad? Yeah,
Ahmad. Ahmad Kaddafi. Good job.
Okay. Okay. So, we're going to do over
here. Go. Okay. Now, look at my screen
and let's go to firewall rules. And we
need to allow firewall rules in here.
Okay. So, first uh basically what I'm
going to do is just allow all of these.
All right. To make my life better. So,
this is going to be allow SSH, allow
RDP, allow MP, and allow VPC custom. And
this is Well, wait, hold on. No, let's
not do that one.
>> Top one is internal traffic to the VPC.
>> Oh, that's internal to VM communication.
>> Okay. Okay. That'll be all right. So not
protocol priority place. Okay, thanks.
All right, so that's okay then. Um, so I
went ahead and allowed them. You have to
allow this because we can't do anything.
There's lot. Okay, you need RDP. You
need SSH. So it's going to allow that by
default and you're also your default VPC
allows it as well. So we have those from
the firewall rules. Just kind of makes
my life a little easier.
Now as we noticed uh in um AWS in AWS
the security group is an object and you
do your security group and then you
basically you do the security group then
you apply it to your VPC or you do the
security group first then you apply it
to your uh EC2. In GCP we don't do this
in GCP. We while we're doing the VPC
while we're making the object we just go
ahead and make the firewall. Um also in
Azure they do it also this method. To be
honest as security guy I prefer to have
a security group make it first as an
object and then apply it to another
object. It makes my life a lot better
and easier as security professional.
This way is also good as long as you
know what you're doing and not everybody
knows what they're doing. Okay.
go down here and I'm going to just do
regional routing for now and keep that
as legacy. That's fine. And I'm going to
do create. Now, if you want to see one
thing here, equivalent command line,
just say no. It gives you
all this information. So, if you want to
do this with your command line, you can
just say no. We'll do this a little bit
later. going.
Oh.
I'm really having a spasm. I don't know
why.
I'm going to have to roll out
after this. There you go.
There you go.
>> Too close. The don't leave us yet.
>> No, I'm I'm not gonna leave you guys.
That's a part of the therapy.
Just Just so you know, part of my
therapy is uh Theo, you're not going to
die and you can't die and you have to be
there for your students. That the
therapist really drilled that into my
head. So, you're you're not going to
die. Stop this.
This took a while for me to accept,
right? I was telling my admins about
this. All of my favorite archetypes
um die without reproduction.
And my uh therapist was like, "Okay,
let's change this.
Everybody you like, you look up to dies
without making a child. Let's let's get
people who actually die." Well, they
they make they reproduce. They have
families and lineage and then they die
afterwards.
All right. Um, black Muslim guided
messages. Sorry I've been so busy. I I
have half the planet trying to contact
me. I'll talk with you after class.
Okay.
>> Thanks.
>> Uh, Trey, what you got?
>> And my audio went out. I couldn't hear
after.
Did you create?
>> We were talking about all the big booty
Latinos that come to your house. That's
what we talked about.
>> Yeah.
>> Theo's house.
>> No, your house. Trey, we went to your
house.
>> Oh, I don't think my wife's going to
like that.
>> Oh, that's too bad. Just she can join
it.
>> Oh, no.
Anyways, uh I see here
>> But
uh so but dynamic routing, did you stay
with regional or select global?
>> It could you could do either one to be
honest. And what about uh the best path
selection mode? It's legacy.
>> No, no, that's you. You're you're
thinking too much. That's great.
>> Got it. Thank you.
>> Okay. All right. So, now we're going to
do is
go over here. Wait, firewall rules.
Let's go over here. Default.
Let's go to firewall. What we got here?
Oh, that's allow HTTP. Oh, that's right.
Okay, that's fine. Okay, so I'm going to
go over here to default. No, not back
over here. Can I add birthday VPC and
I'm going to go to firewall
and I'm going to create a firewall rule.
Okay, so I'm going do here. Follow me
when I'm doing this right now. Go back
over to here. I have ver birthday VPC.
I'm clicking on birthday VPC. Okay. And
then it says firewalls over here. I'm
going to click on the firewall.
Okay.
And then it's going to say down here
create firewall rule. And I'm going to
go and click on that one.
And I'm going to name this one HTTP.
and
HTTP.
Okay. And say on
and type of traffic direction of traffic
is going to be ingress. Yep. Action
unmatch allow. Yes. And
um IP version ranges. Yep.
Source.
All done.
0.0.0.0.
Okay.
Okay. And
protocols and let's just start with
this. Okay. So, protocols and port
specified protocols and port. Go to TCP.
Now, I need a port 80.
Okay.
I'm going to sit here for a second.
So
here it says name is going to be HTTP
description HTTP that's it
and then birth name is birthday VPC
priority 1000 which is fine direction of
traffic is ingress be into your network
uh action on match allow and then
specify target tags. I'm not going to do
anything with this one right now. If I
have to, then I'll do it, but I don't
I'm not going to do it. And then
destination filter. I'm going
destination for later. Protocols and
ports. Specified protocols and ports.
TCP port 80. Okay.
And
ah, shoot. Screw it.
Uh, targets all instances in the
network. There we go.
That's what I want.
Hey there, where it says uh source IP u
v4 source IP 0.0.0
>> four zeros 0.0.0.0
zero slashz
this means all
I'm saying it any anywhere from the
internet can come in
okay
yousef I haven't hit the button yet
I was about to hit the button hadn't
prayed went back and looked I was like
there I know I did something wrong I
could just tell God God came over here
and said yo
did something wrong Okay.
Okay. Allow
uh destination filter.
I don't want that. Nothing. Okay.
Now,
as is the practice before we make a VPC,
what do we do before we make a we say
create the VPC?
Chewbacca.
>> Chewbacca.
We hung Chewbacca.
I didn't know that was a part of the
protocol. No, I don't think that was it.
Hold on.
What? Look at the chat. Pray for
Brazilian cheeks. Really? No. No. No. We
pray. Pray. We pray first so that it
works. Okay. Because maybe it doesn't
know. WILL COX. NO. HARAM, HARAM, HARAM,
JAIL, JAIL. YEAH,
HARAM. Pray to God. Pray. You can say
pray to Allah like Muslim. That's fine.
I can say Allah, too. Okay. Prayer
changes every That's right. So, you
pray. You pray. Okay.
Hold on. We'll see. Yeah, this should
work. Tiqs, it should work. Okay. So
here create.
Woohoo.
And it worked.
Okay.
Good.
Is there a reason why we chose four
firewalls instead of the five?
>> Yeah. I'm I did the fifth one right
there.
>> This has a knack built into it and It's
just all in one spot.
>> Yeah. Uh, TIQS port 22 is automatic. It
gave you the port 22. See, allows SSH.
It's in here already. And so, we allow
VPC construction. Allow ICMP is on
there. And allow RDP is also on there.
So, um, what is that? 3389 is there.
Yeah, that port is going to be there.
And then ICMP is be there with all those
protocols. Um, Black Muscle, what do you
got? So, at this point, just real quick,
now you should have five firewall rules.
Theo might not have his yet. He might
have to hit refresh, but he just made
the fifth one, but it's not a default
rule. It's a custom rule.
>> Yeah.
>> No, I was saying like
>> he meant the default subnet. He was
asking why the default subnet had five
and why ours have four.
>> The the default doesn't have five.
>> No, it Well, hold on. What I did real
quick, just so you know, let's be
honest. I went I looked at the firewall
rules and my default had five.
>> Yeah. One gets one gets created. Yeah.
When you made a VM, if you choose the
>> when I made the VMs before and the other
lamps, I said allow HTTP, right? So that
created a firewall rule in my default.
So the only thing I did is real quickly
I went over there, went over here, and I
looked that HTTP was allowed here. And I
said, "Okay, well then let's just go
over here and do it in birthday VPC. Do
the same thing."
Boom. Got it right there.
That's it.
And Aaron did explain this.
Yeah.
All right.
Haram. Haram. Haram.
Warox. Haram.
All right. So,
>> no, I was uh I was saying like uh the
the knackle and the um um SG are all in
one spot and then if you decide to uh
I'm asking actually if you decide to uh
have a you know a a compute engine that
has https on it, do I have to come here
and enable it first and then
>> No, no, you it's either or. Let me
explain.
Okay. So, what we're going to do is
create a VM. Okay. VM.
>> Mhm.
>> Create a VM.
Now,
this is where the VM gets important.
Okay.
So, I'm going to do is VM in
my VPC.
Okay. Now, I'm putting this is going to
import it. See this region right here?
I'm choosing Iowa. Listen. Listen to
what I'm saying. Write this down. Don't
[ __ ] this up. Okay?
You need to choose the region where you
made your VPC.
Okay?
You need to choose the region where you
made your VPC. So, if you did Dallas,
that means you got to scroll all the way
down to Dallas and go find it. Let's go
here. Let's find it. We'll see. Where's
Where's Dallas?
Do I Do I have Dallas here? Great. I
don't have Dallas. Oh, no. I have
Dardis. So, if you chose Dallas, that's
where you go. You go right here. You
have to choose Dallas. Okay. If you
chose Sao Paulo, you got to go find Sao
Paulo. There's Sao Paulo. You have to
choose your region. Make sure you get
this right. Okay. So, my region is Iowa.
Okay. It's default. Easy to use. Make
sure you get this right because if you
don't, you won't be able to see your
VPC. Okay, next. Keep this as normal.
Keep this all normal as stuff, right?
I'm going go OS storage. Don't change
anything here. Data protection. No
backups.
Networking kind of an important thing
here. Okay. Now, hold on. Leland, what
you got?
>> Yeah, just the dumb 5-year-old question.
Why? Why does it have to match?
>> Because you put it there.
>> Talking about the regions.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Like
>> so we talked about this. This is like
it's a regional resource like or well
maybe we didn't explicitly talk about
it. I write my notes
>> at this point. The way I did it I did it
regional. I didn't do it global. I'm
teaching them regional first.
So because when we we made the VPC, you
had to choose a region, right?
That means that VPC is only in that
region.
So if you're in a if you're making their
EC2 and you choose another region, that
means that the VPC that you made is not
in that region.
>> Makes sense. So to make sure I
understand, so the VPC is like the the
thing that secures the VM.
>> No, no, it's your compute environment.
It's your network.
>> Okay.
>> Your VM requires a network.
>> Okay. So before when we did the
networking, we didn't do anything with
networking because it was already your
default.
Now, we're not using default. Remember
that little script that we have on
there?
>> Mhm.
>> That script will tell me if you did the
default network or your own network.
That's why that script is there because
it tells me what you're actually
configuring and how you're configuring
your environment.
All right,
>> makes sense. Thank you.
>> See, demonic Theo's evil, right? Evil.
Evil Theo going to hell. That's right.
Black Muslim, send me to hell. Okay.
What you got?
>> Hey, listen up, guys. I want y'all to
stop this right now. This idea that you
your questions are stupid. It's
typically the guys who ask questions,
who get the certifications, who get the
jobs. The guys who are quiet, I don't
want I'm too scared to ask. My [ __ ] is
too wet. I can't ask no questions. I
can't do nothing. Those guys, they just
fail. And then they come to Single A and
then they come to me. So ask questions.
Like stop being afraid to ask question.
You don't know it. I guarantee you
somebody else in here has has the same
question. So ask the question. All
right. Good job, Leland. Tonight,
Leland, you need to go look up
networking. What is a network? You need
to go right to YouTube when this class
is over and and watch what is a network.
And whoever else doesn't know, you need
to watch the same videos. What is a
network? And you guys should be like
already making friends or in groups or
whatever. Share with your group. Put it
in your group chat. Hey guys, just just
see if this works for you. I just I
watched this video and it worked for me.
Okay,
>> see if people can remember that. All
right,
that was well stated. Uh Trey,
>> yeah. Uh how did you get to that page?
>> To what page?
>> To the instance page.
>> You were in class the last two weeks,
right? Yes. So, you didn't you didn't
access this from your uh from the VPC?
>> No, you go to the top and do it as nor
like we did last two weeks.
>> Okay. All right. Okay. I thought you did
something different.
>> No.
>> Okay.
>> Same.
>> Same process.
>> Stuff. Yeah.
>> The cloud is really really repetitive.
>> Okay.
>> Right.
>> I just I want to show if you had another
way. I know some alternative.
>> No. Terraform
allow
>> uh for like most of the time we never
enable backups. Is that because we're
just taking it slow? Because usually
like in AWS or whatever we've done
before.
>> This is your lab and you have to pay for
those resources and I don't want you to
have a lot of backups and maybe have a
charge on it. If you're in the office,
you're doing backups all the time
because it's their money, not yours.
>> Okay.
Okay.
But you can take a backup if you want
to. I mean, I know you're rich. I know
you're richer than me. So, if you're
like, "Hey, I got the money. I'm just
going to do a backup. I don't care if
there's a backup." Go for it, bro. I'm
not I have no problems with it. Go do
your backup. I'm not
I'm not going to argue with you. Be
like, "Hey, this guy got this guy's got
some money, man. He doing a backup."
Okay. Uh, hold on.
Yes. Are you sure? Okay.
>> When I was 23 years old, I turned this
smoothie king from this to this. I got
the crazy idea to submit my Jesus.
>> You are to be nice to us. Okay. Be nice
to us. I have enough stress today. My
back is popped for some reason.
Something's going on. I'm teaching on my
birthday. Be nice.
Be nice to me. Okay. Network tags. We're
not going to do any network tags. We're
going to do this later on. Uh host name.
Not going to do anything with the host
name.
I'm gonna do Okay, fine. Uh birthday.
Can I do that?
Uh, let's just do let's just do default.
That's fine. Okay. IP foring.
Uh, I don't I do IP foring? No, I don't
need this. Okay. Network interfaces
here. Go to network interfaces.
Network.
Be see here. Network. I'm changing my
network. Before my network was default.
Now, my network is birthday VPC.
If you don't find your
specialized VPC, it means you're in the
wrong region.
Okay.
Now, let me show you how this works
because I'm sure some people are not
going to understand this.
>> Uh, I think they'll see the VPC. It just
won't let them choose the subnet because
>> No, no. Uh well,
>> it's global the VPC. So they'll still
see it in whatever region.
>> It should be regional. We'll see the two
style Apollo here. And now I'm going to
go networking
and network interfaces default. Oh yeah.
Okay, it does see it.
But your subnets
>> you're thinking AWS, remember here the
VPC.
>> Well, I I knew that. Okay. Okay. So you
can see this VPC, but you can't do a
subnet here.
But if you go to here and see I have my
network is birthday VPC the subnet Corny
appears automatically.
All right. See how that that works kind
of nice. So if you
did if you did not choose the correct
region you will not be able to go into
the pro your specialized subnet. Okay.
show it to you guys again. Over here,
I chose Sao Paulo. When I go to
networking,
see here, there's a default I can use or
I can use birthday VPC, but it doesn't
have the subnet doesn't come up. That's
because the subnet isn't in Sa Paulo. I
configured the subnet in Iowa.
So, here it is. The corny subnet isn't I
got it.
>> Uh, do we need to allow HTTP traffic or
No.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Look, I'm not not dealing
with that. We already did that with the
firewall rule. Get to that. I I need to
make sure people get this right cuz
people undoubtedly are not going to get
this right. They're going to come back
for troubleshooting. I need to shoot
this down right now. This happened every
year that I've taught this and I have to
make sure this is done correctly.
All right. Subnet card.
Uh, what is a sum card?
It should be. Yeah, just let it be by
default.
Yeah, it's made by default. Okay.
Okay. So, I'm going to go back up to
here
and allow HTTP traffic. Yes.
Okay,
guys. You guys always know. Because
always, if you're doing this lab, you
always allow HTTP. Always.
>> Why do you allow HTTP traffic?
>> How?
>> Why? Why?
>> Uh, it's because we want to sniff
Chewbacca's booty. That's why. So, port
80 is allowed to sniff his booty.
>> Okay.
>> So, they know why the last two weeks.
>> But for the job, Theo, why
>> for the job? The smell your manager's
booty. That's why. Hey,
>> answer legit.
>> No, no snark. Just give them a reason
why you do port 80.
>> Class, why do you have to why are we
doing port 80?
>> Oh my god.
>> So,
I hate you.
>> so when you're in the when you're you
got to think about we're in the cloud.
We're in the internet, right?
>> Wait, is that Carlos D? No, no, no, no.
I want a new guy or Theo. Okay.
>> Sorry.
>> Oh,
>> come on. Who wants to be brave and
unmute?
>> Bash. Got it.
>> Can you repeat that, please?
>> Okay. Why do you select HTTP allow?
>> Because HTTP is how you access um the
internet.
That's correct.
>> He said don't use HTTPS.
>> Yeah, you use HTTPS to uh access it
publicly over the internet or a
>> get a little more confused, but you're
in correction.
>> HTTP is how you access like basic uh
public things cuz we're not we're not on
a secured server, which that would take
something extra that we're not doing.
Correct. That's That's more correct.
Yes, it's more correct.
>> Okay. All right.
>> All right. Theo, do you want to clarify?
>> Hey, dude. It's good.
>> Hey, look.
>> Rob,
>> you want to add your spice to it,
please? As a senior engineer, please.
>> So,
>> no, no, no. I can do it. I can do it.
>> You know what? No problem. Go ahead. Go
ahead, guy.
>> Do it, please.
>> So, here's the thing, right? When you're
on the internet and you want to move
things throughout the internet, it's all
based on very specific protocols, right?
And these protocols have very specific
jobs to do things in very specific ways.
The reason we have to uh use HTTP is
because that's the one that you use,
especially when you're trying to hit
like a web like a a website through the
web browser. If you look at your URL,
right, and you put in whatever website,
you know, at the beginning, it usually
will say like HTTP,
that's telling the protocol. The reason
it's up there is it's specifying the
protocol so it does so it knows how to
send it the correct way that it can
understand what's being sent so that
it's sent and it's given the correct
way. That's why we use HTTP. Port 80,
that's the specific port, right? So, it
kind of tells it where to hit on that
server. So, it's kind of like you could
think of it like when you have your web
address, it points it to the computer,
but that port then tells it where on
that computer to look for it. So, that
that's why since we're trying to access
it on the internet, usually through a
web browser, you have to think HTTP,
right? And since it's unsecure,
it's going to be HTTP port 80. It'll be
something else if it was secure. But
right now, that's how you should think
of it. If I want to go and I want to hit
this website, but I want to do it the
way through like a web browser, how you
display it. HTTP
port 80 for unsecure. There's a secure
one, but right now that's unsecure. When
you do things with secure, it makes it a
lot more confusing, a lot more
difficult. We're not going to go into
that. We just want to make it pop up and
see some [ __ ] So that's why HTTP port
80. Okay.
Thank you.
>> Okay.
Is that good, Rob?
>> If if you want to add on, go for it.
>> No, I feel like it would derail things.
>> Then
Theo can continue with his glowing snark
because this is birthday.
>> One question.
>> Where do we put the We're networking,
right? Where do we put the port 80?
>> No, it's right here. Right there like
last last two weeks.
>> Oh, okay. Port 80 is a part of that.
>> No, that is port 80.
>> That is port 80. So, a lot of HTTP
traffic is port 80.
>> Yeah, HTTP is port 80.
>> Oh, thank you. Thank you. Gotcha.
>> SSH is almost always port 22. We're
going to go over that later a little
later on. But just there are certain
services which are always pretty much
always assigned to a certain port.
God, my back. Okay.
Okay. Next,
go to advanced. We need a startup
script.
So, I'm go back over to GitHub.
Sir
weekly lessons
week a user scripts
basic.
Okay,
let's do this one. Copy raw file.
You can copy any of these you want. I
don't care.
Where is it? Over here. Ouch. Starcript.
Paste. Okay,
there we go.
There we go. Should be everything we
need. We got everything we need right
here. Sounds good. We We correct We did
the correct subnet. We have the We have
a custom VPC. We We should be good.
Okay. Great.
Okay. And wait a little bit.
Okay,
back
[ __ ] All right.
All right. Got to wait for this.
Now, when this done, the first test I'm
going to do is make sure SSH works.
SSH should work. If SSH doesn't work, we
have an issue. So, I need to make sure
SSH works.
So, let it keep on spinning.
And my back feels horrible. I have no
idea why.
It was a lot worse on Monday. This is
This is pretty bad, but Monday was bad.
You can use any script you want. I don't
care.
Okay, connect here. First thing I'm
going to do is do SSH connection. Make
sure that works.
Transferring key to the VM.
Authorize.
Okay, good. Port 22 works.
This is important. So, if port 22 works,
then I know the rest of my command
should pretty much work. Everything
should be okay. But I need to do this
first to make sure my firewalls are
correct. All right.
So, that works. Good. Now, I need to do
is test port 80. You can do a curl
command to do test port 80 also, but I'm
not going to do that right now.
Go to here. http
colon/ slash paste.
There we go.
That worked.
It worked. My port 80 worked. My custom
firewall war worked. My unerscript
worked. And I did this all in a custom
VPC. Good.
Okay. Now, let's go. Carlton.
So, we got
Jay Herrera.
You redo that one more time.
>> Jay Herrera, you didn't do uh
you didn't evidence for me. I don't know
if it's working or not. Carlton.
Yeah, see Carlton.
Yeah, that's all done. DPC.
>> See, you guys see this is this is why I
know. See this? See this right here?
Instant sticky buns. VPC sticky bud.
See, all I need, all I did is I'll go
look at that. I said, "Yeah, I know this
is a c. I know he did it right because
GCP would never name their their VPC by
default as Dicky Buns." See that? See
how easy it is? I'm like, "Yep, I know
that's the correct one. Don't have to
spend much time there." I know he did it
right. Thomas,
am I sharing my screen?
Okay. Yep. Good.
Lonnie.
Yep. There it is. Lonx class 75 VPC. You
crazy. You crazy. Thomas. Yes. Girl.
Okay. J. Correct. Good. Okay. DeAndre,
the section where you're having a
problem. take a screenshot of it and put
into the chat so people can work with
you while I'm doing this.
All right, Lavarius,
good job,
Logan. Too easy for you, Logan.
There you go. Yep. Good job, Logan.
That's what I like to see. Carlton.
Oh, no. Done the right ways. Okay. Thank
God.
Okay, William. Sorry, Wilcox.
Good.
I'm laughing Dominic cuz I'm just
thinking like later on people asked me
your 53rd birthday, what were you doing?
I was like uh GCP and Liso.
How many birthdays did you have while
you're doing Lisa? Oh, I had like the
last five birthdays I had with Lisa.
Okay, good.
My goal now is to make sure I don't go
to the hospital like I did two years
ago.
Jal Jalil. Good. Jonathan Hill.
Good. Look at that.
See, was it was it hard? Did anybody
die? Daniel
good.
Lavarius
are she want to leave Waffle House.
Lavarius. Good. Wow.
You actually want to leave. They want to
leave it. Ernest
man. Big pack.
Good.
Good job, Ernest.
Karim,
good.
Claude,
are you are you AI? Good.
Christopher,
good.
Martinez.
Martz. Sorry, Martz. I'm going to get
your name right. Okay. I'm trying.
Good.
Nico.
Niko.
Good job, Nico.
Lyall.
Good. Wow. Good job. Okay. Great.
Nest egg.
Good job. Like it.
Christopher Hunter.
Good job.
William Hana.
Woo. Good job.
Kevin,
good job
below.
Good job, Chuck.
Wow.
Bacus.
Good.
Kelly Moore.
Kelly Moore. Good.
Carlton. Uh, I don't know what that is.
Uh, oh, that's fine.
Okay, Mr. Oh god, Mr. K,
good job.
Okay, good. Port 22 is working. Good.
Josh Ox
good
birthday VPC okay
goodin
good
Leland
Good
tray.
Good.
Wait, what? Okay.
Okay.
Alex Felder.
Alexa,
Alexa.
Yep. Alex, your page isn't resolving. I
can't tell why.
So, Whoa. Yep. Um, so you need to
actually um
uh make sure your port 22 is open and
then kernel make sure port 80 is open.
But to make sure it's probably your port
80 just isn't open. You didn't allow
HTTP. That's it. Okay. J Herrera.
Good.
Herbert Jackson.
Good. Kaddafi.
Ahmad. Gaddafi.
Very good. Irwin.
Okay. I like that. Good.
Okay.
The second pen do. Yeah. Yeah. No,
you're fine. Good job. Good job. Good
job. Uh, okay.
>> Lavarius, you're never leaving Waffle
House. You're staying there forever. In
fact, I'm going to make a Waffle House
in Colia just so you can be a passport
bro over there at the same place of
employment.
Govern
>> Jay's works. I think it was probably
still bootstrapping.
>> I like it.
Good
parl.
No. Yeah, it's non deliverable. Goblin.
Good job.
Michael Michael.
Michael Dale.
Good. Really? Okay. Okay. There. See?
See? Big booty gal. See that? You can
see this is a fun thing. You get to use
you get to use your naming convention to
have fun. You can see this. It's a it's
a nerdy thing to do, but it's fun.
>> Mhm.
>> Albert.
Okay.
Good.
Rio,
do it now. You got free time.
Albert, good. Dwayne
good
ad.
I like it. I like the
>> the motivation. The motivation to do
this uh was it James? He got hired
making $85 an hour. took him a year, but
he was he was pushing hard. So, learn
it.
>> Learn it. Yeah.
>> Yeah. To that. Um I'll add to that. I uh
just finished my first week of work.
Making over 100K a year, guys. So,
>> real man, it's real.
>> Whoa. When did you get hired?
>> Uh
>> two two and a half weeks ago.
>> Yeah. Thanks, guys.
>> One. Congratulations, sir.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Thanks a lot, Jose. I
appreciate it. Um, I was uh Jules helped
me out a lot, man. Jules is a tough one
you guys when you come to that uh speed
shop, so you got to go.
>> Um, but uh it's a it's a S. So, you know
what I'm saying?
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Very nice.
>> Hey, can you do me a favor? Can you send
me a uh a DM with the information? All
right. Okay.
>> What's the title?
>> Uh S for Hun.
>> No, no. Put put this in the DM though.
>> Oh. Oh, okay.
>> Just for tracking. What's the title?
What's the wages?
>> Um what class did you start with? Class,
you know, three, four, five, you know,
5.5, whatever.
>> And then have you done speech ops? Have
you done resume ops?
>> Oh, yeah. Absolutely. Okay.
>> Thank you, sir. I love that.
Black Muslims been on it for a while.
Cook it. I like to hear that direct
deposit is like let me get some steak
tonight.
>> Yeah, I gota
I mean
>> I want steak. That sounds good.
>> I want steak.
>> That's some birthday steak of steak.
>> I got no steak. Oh no, I got no steak
for me tonight. I wish. No steak. No
steak for me.
Okay.
Okay. Hold on. Let's go back to here.
Couchi.
Yep. GOOD.
That was good. Couch. Good job.
Okay.
Ter. Okay. So, Terrell, your
your
Okay.
Your your port 22 is is good.
um real uh if you're really having again
just go do the UDMI it's the exact same
thing on a demi we're not doing anything
really that different okay
this is the first time you're in class
right for VP for VPC I think but that's
because this this is week three so this
is like the for some of the students
this is like the fifth time we've gone
over but it's okay you'll you'll get
you'll get used to it
Um, time for the second line.
I don't know about that, man. I don't
know.
Okay, good job, Xavier. Good,
Mr. K.
Good. I like that, Mr. K. Good job.
Kevin Till
good
like it like this will be Saturday
afternoon I'm teaching that'd be great t
oh no not tiqs
okay
good thank god
I'm having copying DeAndre. We did this
last two weeks. All you do is copy it
here
and then you go over to the VPC, go to
advance and you paste it there. You're
not putting it into a search bar. We
never put into a search bar. It always
goes into the advanced section here in
automation. Always.
Always. This is where it goes. It does
not go into a search bar. You do not put
a script into a search bar.
Please don't do that. You can get into
serious trouble doing that. Do not do
that. Please.
>> So, I I did that. I put an automation. I
hit create and wait for it to pop up so
I can copy it
>> then so I could put the http.
>> No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no. Make sure you understand what it is.
You make it, you get the external IP.
You don't say it say I looked for the
external IP. The external IP was here
and you copied it here,
>> right?
>> And then you did http colon/paste
there.
>> What do you call that? Do you call that
the search bar? Well, how would I do
that so I can say the right
pronunciation?
>> Say I put it into the URL.
>> The URL. I did that and it's not showing
up. I guess I
>> It's not showing up. So then what you
probably did was this networking. You
didn't allow HTTP traffic.
>> You have to always do that. We did that
last two weeks.
>> What
IP in the chat? I'll I can tell you
right now if you have port 80 open or if
it's your starter script.
>> Yep.
>> I I don't know who it is though.
>> Hey Phil, I have a quick question.
>> Hold on. Hold on. Hold on. Hold on. Put
your hand up. Put your hand up.
>> Oh, you're right. You're right.
>> Um, Alex Felder, good job.
I'll get to you, Miles, but just put it
up to Clay. I got it.
>> Mhm.
>> So, ordering it here.
>> Yes,
>> John.
>> No problem.
>> Williams. Good.
Yes. Below, that's you're you're saying
it exactly correct. That's that's what I
was thinking. That was a good URL
explanation.
Okay, Yousef.
Good. New
land. I like that. I like it. Yousef.
Good. Snarky. Like it. Good job, Jerome.
Oh, no. Not Jerome. Oh, no. Not Jerome.
Why are you gonna do something? I knew
you gonna do Okay.
Yes. Yes. Good. Good job, Jerome. Okay,
Jerome Hunter, you have better get a job
for 150,000.
If you get if you can be snarky like
that, I want you 150,000. Okay.
>> Yes. Yes. Absolutely.
>> Yeah. Yes. Yes. I will. I shall I shall
do it. 150,000. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Minimum. Thank you. Great.
>> Okay. Now, Miles, what you got?
Yeah, I forgot to document it when I uh
did the steps for the VM um a few
moments ago, but since we made the VPC
and we added the um HTTP rule for the
firewall, did it automatically um tick
the allow HTTP
when we were making the um
>> No, it doesn't. You need to make it for
the firewall. But also, let me
>> Okay, if you check, let's go over here.
>> This is why for why I know, okay, if you
allow, if you click this one, it's
allowing port 80 for the asset directly
and that you're making right here. And
then it's also, if this is the first
time that you do it for your VPC, it
might also create it there. So, I'm
assuming that it creates there. I don't
know to be honest because I don't do
default. I don't use a default network.
All right. So, I'm always making my own
VPC. So, my own VPC, of course, I'm
going to do allow it in the firewall and
then I'm also going to do allow it with
the object.
>> So, okay.
>> I Yeah, I I could clarify that real
quick.
>> Yeah. Uh so we when when you created the
VM you made a custom firewall rule for
TCP80.
So that would open HTTP traffic from the
public internet uh uh for the VPC and he
targeted all instances.
So right here the allow HTTP traffic
option it's not really needed. What it
will do when you create the VM if you
check it is it's going to create an
additional firewall rule and in that
firewall firewall rule instead of
targeting all instances it's going to be
using something called a target tag and
then it's going to spec it's going to
call it httpy- server and it's going to
add that tag to the VM. So either or
will work but uh ju just so you
specifically know what's going to
happen. Like that's why in your default
VPC you see uh one firewall rule for
port 80 that has a tag of HTTP server is
because you have made a VM before in the
default VPC and you've checked that
option.
So it's so when we go into firewalling,
we're going to have a specific section
on firewalling. We're going to do the
tag uh firewalling via tagging which is
and and GCP is an amazing concept and
idea. It's it's really cool. Um it's the
way to do it, but for now to make life
easy, we're just doing it this way.
Well, the way that Aaron explained it is
what we're that's where we're going to
at the end.
>> Gotcha. Thanks, guys.
>> No problem.
Okay. Does anybody else have any
questions
besides is my back broken or do I have
five big booty Latinas in my bedroom or
am I going to a strip club after after
this with big booty Latinas?
I'm sure you guys have all kinds. Okay,
Friday, Theo's birthday. He's single. He
has a lot of money. He can do anything
he wants. Yeah, it's big booty Latina.
>> I take it easy Latina.
>> If I did go out, it'd probably be uh
pancake white girl. That be honest.
That's probably what I go for. But
>> not the Dr. Uber.
>> The last the last big booty girl that I
was with like in Chicago left me
exhausted. So I didn't know what to do
after that. So,
I'm going to think about that again.
Anyway,
Carlton with the cloud audience. I liked
how BTS were had the show today and he's
talking about how like like we're doing
fine. We're doing this fine, but the
women are starting to suffer. And the
women burned their bridges
and now they have to deal with where
they are.
>> No rational man should be dealing with
them at all at this point.
>> Yep. AMS pointed that out too in his
recent videos. Well, he's got like a
reaction channel now. And yeah, those
women are hollering bad. Real bad.
>> Yeah, they're they're just division. Um,
so the men aren't doing well there's a
lot less simps. So there's a lot less
they can't offer the what is the promise
of sex. They can't do that cuz the men
are going to be like we know you're not
going to screw us so we're not going to
give you any money. We're not even going
to try
and just walking away. And then the men
are using the money for themselves which
is smart.
The women don't know what to do. Um, I
know with my female friends that I have
like I I'm talking with them. Uh, most
of them if if they're single, they are
suffering at this point. The married
women are doing just fine. No problems.
Outside the matrix. Good. Kent, that's
not what you do. No. No. That's not a
hyperlink. Kent, you didn't do it right.
Trey. Yeah, AC was good last night.
Betray your branch at all.
Oh boy.
Okay. Am I lying?
Okay. Um Okay. Do you guys have any
questions?
Yeah. I'm going to show you how I'm
going to show you one more time how to
make the instance and VPC.
Go here. Create instance.
>> Sorry. Uh Theo question. Um I know the
BM that we create if we leave it up will
cost us money. Will the VPC that we
create cost us anything or do we have to
tear that down directly as well?
>> You should tear it down.
>> Okay.
So once we're done so being done with
the this VM just tear it down now that
we're done with it.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That's easy. Uh
>> how do we get rid of the V uh P? I'll
tell you. I got to do this first. I got
Sorry. I can't show I got to do this.
Um, hold on.
There you go. Now, here you got US
Central. I'm doing Iowa again. Not doing
anything with this part. Making sure I'm
the right region. Okay. Go to OS
storage. Everything's fine here. Data
protection. No backups. Networking.
Remember networking.
Allow HTTP traffic. This is the same as
it was before. Always allow HTTP HTTP
traffic. Okay. Next,
we go down here. Network interfaces.
Click here for nick network says
default. Click birthday or whatever your
custom VPC. Click on that. And see, I
have my subnet automatically populated.
Nice.
Later on, we're going to make more
subnets, but for now, keep just one
subnet. Okay? And then we don't have to
do anything else for the rest of this.
Go to advanced. Says automation startup
script.
Go to my repo.
Go to user scripts.
I'm going to use super a
copy it.
Go back.
paste. Okay.
Then create.
Same as last time.
This one I don't need it. The first one
I don't need it. I don't want to be
build. So I'm going to get cancel it.
Delete that one.
Okay, going to
Okay, got it. So, this is BD party.
First thing I'm going to do here is go
to SSH. Make sure it works. Authorize.
Yes.
Okay. So, part 22 works good. Now have
external IP. I'm going to copy this.
Going to copy the external IP. Go to my
URL. http colon slash paste. Boom.
Now, this one works. And now my VPC is
birthday VPC. There it is. And it has my
network range right there.
Whoa. Eva, Eva, Eva,
Eva, keep
the
Eva was having a nightmare.
She was yelping in her sleep.
Let me make sure
I feel good. I feel good. Okay.
So,
there is. And now you can look at mine.
There's mine right there.
Dominic,
it takes a while to deploy. That's
normal.
Okay.
Um, James Kent.
Good. Dusty Seir. I like that.
Very good.
Okay.
Ernst. Earnest.
Okay, good job.
Good job, Ernest. You want that money?
I'm going to get it.
I want that money.
Give me the money. I want the money. I
want your name. Some unknown. Wait a
minute.
What? How did that happen?
Yeah, subnet unw. That is weird.
You should have a subnet.
That's odd. I don't know how that one
worked.
Good eye, Carlton.
U Mr. Alex K.
Yeah, that's that's what why what's
going on? normally.
>> Uh, you don't.
Yeah. Yeah, that's
>> Oh, mine is also subet unknown. That's
odd.
Okay. Okay, fine. Uh, maybe the script
isn't picking that one up. That's all I
can say.
Martz.
Okay, good. Good, Martz. Good job.
Okay.
Dom Nick.
Okay. Good. Yep. Good. Good.
Sleep well. Ted.
Okay. Danger.
You may
Lonnie.
Okay. Lonnie, good.
Leavaria is good.
Logan, good.
Oh. Oh, I was removing
I'm in the wrong place. Hold on.
Okay, Leland.
Very good.
Josh,
good. Where where did Josh go? Okay,
Lind.
Good.
Kevin Jones.
Good. I like that. Kevin Jones did a
great job.
Mr. Alex K.
>> Good.
And you got your port 22 up. Good. Okay.
Good.
Okay. Good. So, I like what we have so
far. I think you guys did a great job.
Um, if you guys want to get rid of your
VPC,
to tell you the truth, the VPC doesn't
cost that much to operate it uh in in
GCP. It's cost is negligible, but we're
just going to get rid of it anyway. So,
go here. Go Oh, hold on. Hold on. Let's
make sure first tear down your resource.
Okay. Wait for a second to tear down.
I'm going to go to a VPC next. Make sure
you you erase your VM first.
Then go to VPC networks.
Okay. And I got birthday VPC. Just go
ahead and click on here. And
wait, where's
Wait, wait, wait. Is that it?
Wait, where's my delete button? Oh,
there it is. Delete VPC right there.
I need glasses.
Just go ahead and click on it and then
you're done. Okay,
I'm going to keep my VPC my birthday VPC
up. So, it's my birthday. I'm going to
go and keep it up for you. I like my
birthday VPC.
You know, I do my best for you guys. You
know, I want you all to be successful. I
want you guys to be um in happy
relationships. Um a lot of you guys
haven't taken as much damage as I have.
I I've I've truly taken horrific damage.
Uh so that's why I'm in I'm basically in
trauma therapy. Um, but you guys don't
have, well, some areas you guys do have
it as bad as I do. In some ways, you
guys don't do. So, it's one of my goals
to have see a lot of you guys abroad,
married, happy, making children, right?
So, let's let's hope for the best there,
but not everybody will do this. It's
okay. You know, there'll be a future for
you. Um, I hope all of you are
successful, though. See you guys being
successful.
All right. Uh, do you have any questions
before class ends and you guys start
making jokes about whether or not I'm
going to a strip club?
>> One more time of breaking that down for
me.
>> Breaking it down?
>> Yeah, one more time for me, please.
>> Okay, so go to the VM section and you
delete your VMs and then you go to the
VPC section and you delete your VPCs.
So, all you do is I can't I don't have
everything up right now. you go to
create. So this section here I don't
have any VMs up anymore so I can't show
it but this is where you go
or you go to compute engine is it see
overview I have I've got no VMs running
so you have to go to your VM section and
then click on all your VPNs and VMs and
delete them.
8.
>> Does anybody know Does anybody know why
you delete the VM before you delete the
VPC?
>> Anybody
>> stab at it?
>> Won't allow you.
>> Yeah,
>> you got to delete the contents of the
first.
>> You got to first remove any resources
that that depend on that VPC. It's a
dependency there.
>> Yeah.
>> That's right. The VM lives inside of the
VPC. So,
>> got to evict everybody first before you
can shut the house down.
>> It's a redundancy feature. Correct.
>> Not really a redund dependency. It's
it's
>> Yeah.
>> And I mean, in more layman's terms, it
makes sense. Like, hey, like I'm
deleting this VBC. Hey, before we delete
it, this very important instance you
have in here, are you sure you want this
to be destroyed? You know,
>> or it just won't let you do it. It just
won't let you do it regardless. Like,
the system has a dependency clause in it
that will not allow you to
>> get rid of anything that has something
in it. You can only blow up an empty
house. You can't blow up a house with
people in it.
>> Exactly. Exactly.
>> Got you. Understood.
>> I mean,
some some nation states say you can blow
up.
Oh goodness.
>> The war still going on, man.
>> On that note,
>> you got I you just got to think of it.
It has guard rails inside to make sure
you don't do something stupid by
accident, right? Like you just forget
stuff that you'd rather it ask you first
and force you to do like delete what's
inside and outside then you try to
delete a VBC and you need what's inside
of it and now you can't get it back.
Understood. Um, under the VPC, do we
also delete the default one as well?
>> No, no, don't touch the default.
>> Okay. Okay.
Look, at least for the people that which
there's going to be some people that do
delete the default VPC, it's actually
you just need to create a VPC with
automatic subnet creation and then just
set the cider range to the default one.
and it'll create it.
>> Okay. So, it's not world ending if you
delete it. I didn't do it. I'm just
saying I didn't
>> I wouldn't I wouldn't do it. But
>> Okay. Gotcha.
>> It also yours the one you recreate in
place of it costs money. This one is
free.
>> Yeah. Your default is free.
>> It works out in GCP. We we tested it.
But
>> Oh, okay. But I mean, no point in
testing it. It was Baron and I were
curious.
>> You didn't see Theo erase the default
VPC. You won't see him do this in class.
Do not erase default VPC.
All right.
Not going to do that.
Okay. Do not ask questions about it.
Please don't don't do that. Oh, I'm just
going to erase something that Theo isn't
erasing.
You sure about that?
Okay, the studios are racing it for a
reason. Okay. Anyway, um before you guys
keep Okay, no heart attack. You're going
to live going to be happy. Oh, yeah.
Sorry. Yeah, there were going to do some
cool stuff in there. Um
at least he asked a question. That's
true. Yeah, she was in here.
That's good one. Oh, that's good, Trey.
I like it. I like that. That's good.
>> Uh
>> yeah, that was a good one.
>> All right. You guys have any questions?
Yeah, there's
>> It's 9:30.
Yeah, you're supposed not to be teaching
anymore. Supposed to go and take a walk.
>> Yeah, it still won't let me delete this
VPC. It keeps saying to confirm the type
network name, birthday VPC, and it's
red.
>> Did you confirm the name by typing it?
You have to do that. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Copy and paste it in.
>> So,
>> it's just trying to make sure you don't
do something you don't want to do by
accident and delete it. That's why it's
like that.
>> It's un it's you can't undo it. as well.
You want to make sure it's twofrack a
delete. If I say delete VPC and then it
says this confirm, you have to do that
process.
It's not saying you can't do it. You're
you're not following the rules. It's
saying for you to type it in. You type
it in.
AWS does the same thing
irritatingly all the time, but it does
do this,
right?
Okay.
I know you know some good massage
therapists out there, Theo.
>> I don't want a massage therapist. I want
Hennessy.
>> Hennessy. Boy, that's a real negro right
there. Goodness grac
uh the work the work week and uh it's
really good in Morocco. You start
working at like 1:00, get off at 8,
it'll be same here as Eastern and then
you know there's a lot of beautiful
land, palm trees, women that like to
cook for their husbands out.
The necroity is too.
>> Maybe I should go over there. I got my
Arabic book. I should sit there and
study it for a bit. Maybe try. I should
try it. I've got no idea though.
>> Um,
>> a beautiful country for real too.
>> Yeah, I
I I
want
that's all I think about for me.
I should probably No.
>> Who really like Hennessy?
>> I'm not supposed to drink. No, I'm not
going to do it. I will not drink.
>> I I will not.
>> Y'all really like Hennessy for real?
That's crazy.
>> Dude,
>> you know they have those non-alcoholic
drinks now you can buy at the liquor
store, which is ironic to me.
>> Yes.
>> I want to have sex without an orgasm.
Please.
Why? Why are we there?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So, like again, after my wife was
that wife died, I became an alcoholic
for about a year and a half and I
definitely know the tastes of different
alcohol and what it does and how it
processes to your body. I'm very aware.
So, yeah, me and Nike, I like my stuff.
My friends did intervention on me and
made me pour out all my alcohol until
that was I don't know. I think I lost
like $3,000 worth of alcohol in a day.
>> Shout out to the homies.
>> That's some good friends. They sat there
and made you pour that out.
>> It's crazy.
>> Yeah, they made me They actually made me
do it. Like they watched me do it. And
then Kitty, my dog, wasn't too happy
about it. So, she went to the uh street
and started drinking the champagne and
she got drunk.
Yeah. So I do know um alcohol types. I
do like various alcohols. But now I can
drink but if I do drink it's like strict
only one shot.
Well maybe two but that's about it.
I'm very I'm good underlying the I what
I did is I did the work. So the
underlying reason why I was alcoholic
has been resolved. So that means I can
drop him. Uh yes, please go over here
and troll Andre.
Okay. Uh
so just go ahead and say hi to him.
There. So TIQS is in there.
No. CL class 7.5. So class 7.5. We're
doing 7.5 tonight.
All right. Any other questions before I
call it a night?
Break my promise not to drink and drink
a half bottle of Hennessy.
>> Yeah, you're going to call me, right?
>> Yeah, I'm going to cut.
>> Happy birthday, brother. Came in here to
say happy birthday, man. Happy birthday.
Happy birthday. Did
>> a good presentation yesterday, so good.
Thank you
>> guys. I'm going to go and this
>> go on to Andre's channel, say something
over there, okay? He needs the support.
I'll talk to you guys later.
>> Happy birthday to you.