be able to do this class. All right. So,
do it now.
So, tell me if you don't have it. Put a
one in the chat if you don't have this
set up.
Uh RJB, what you got?
>> If it wants to update it, don't worry
about it right now. It's going to take a
while. That's not what Theo was asking.
No, I'm only out. I need you to make
sure that this information here is
there. I don't care if it is update.
This session is live stream. No, no,
Trey. I um What do you
I'm not gonna be stunky. I don't have
time. All right.
Um, what do you get?
What are you guys getting if you when
you got when you guys do your um G-Cloud
info? What is the what? Take a
screenshot of what you're seeing so we
can see it in like we can find out
what's going on.
Where's my dogs? My dog. Yo, don't get
don't get Where's my Don't get
Okay.
No, I didn't say that. No, no, Nest Egg,
I didn't say that. I told you to put in
G-Cloud info.
That's the command. I I didn't whatever
you're doing there. I didn't tell you to
do that. I said G-Cloud info.
What are you doing with that command? I
didn't say that command.
Good.
Very good.
Okay, fine. All right. So, I need to
know if you if you don't have this, then
I need to know it now. Tell me.
>> It's not working for me. I don't have
it.
>> Okay. Take a screenshot. Let me see what
you got.
>> Sure.
No. What do you Okay.
Okay. So, you don't Okay. So, nest egg
you don't have it.
Okay.
And
>> now nest nest
he's a new student. He absolutely does
have it. He it's he's having the
environmental variable issue. He needs
to open the cloud shell and run G-Cloud
info
>> because because regardless like
>> what if you use those clouds
>> if you run the ADC command from the
cloud shell it goes into the same
directory that like Terraform the
Terraform Google provider would look.
>> So like it it doesn't matter where he
runs that G-Cloud command. So you can
run it from the cloud shell and it'll
still work.
>> Yeah. So run it from the Okay, you guys
you guys who have cl the cloud shell
installed, run it from the cloud shell.
>> Okay.
>> So if you're on Windows and you get like
an error that's like when you run try to
run G-Cloud command that says like py
there's an issue with Python or
something sort
uh SDK shell and uh run that and then
run the commands there.
and then have your group fix the Python
issue with G-Cloud for Git Bash later.
>> You can't come in here.
mute if you're not talking.
>> Okay,
>> Estros, you should have the G-Cloud um
shell installed.
Go with that.
>> He's he's on a Mac.
>> Oh,
>> he he's on a really old version of Mac.
I got him a deprecated version of the
SDK installed, but I wasn't confident. I
mean, it it had initialized uh back when
I set it up, but
not sure what's going on, but
it says common not found.
>> Yeah.
Um,
okay.
I don't know.
>> Uh, who who's using a Mac right now?
>> I
>> Quinton.
>> Yes. Yes. Run uh in terminal run the
command which space G-Cloud
which like whi
space G-Cloud and then paste in the chat
what it tells you
>> or Kevin whoever does it first.
>> Go
okay. Oh, okay. It's going to be in the
homebrew path, but uh Estus didn't
didn't use homebrew.
Uh, give me a sec.
Let's see.
I'll wait
>> just one second. Let me just look up
where the binary is on uh
Yeah, estrus. Uh,
if I remember right, we unzipped
this uh
somewhere
on in your computer. There should be a
Google Cloud SDK folder like an
documents or something.
Let me take a look.
All
right.
I'm
he he doesn't he shouldn't have to do
that bash. It's I was the one that
uh extracted the tar uh tarball with
him. It's like in a home directory or
documents. It's like two places to look.
So, Estus, uh, do you see a folder
>> that says like Google Cloud SDK?
>> Uh, not really. I don't see it. Oh, if
you don't, then maybe you deleted it
after we did it, in which case it would
find it.
>> Was it supposed to stay in um
>> Yes,
>> I only deleted deleted um what was in
the download folder, nothing else?
>> It was supposed to stay.
>> Oh,
>> yeah. Let's redo it.
>> Uh that that's going to take a bit of
time. His group can help him with that.
They're going to have to find out. I I
had to look to find which deprecated
version worked and stuff and manually
extract it and add it to the path
variable and So, oh
>> his his group can
>> he's using like a 2012 Mac. So, uh
homebrew doesn't support it.
>> May the Lord be with you.
We can say
>> yep should be able to figure it out
though. just uh have to look back and
and see what version of the the cloud
SDK was supported for that version of
Mac OS.
>> Okay. Okay. So, this is good. Okay. This
is this is good. Now,
um
Okay. So,
um I want you to go to your browser.
Okay. You're actually I'm not going to
this
I don't feel
I'm just feel just be nice and delete.
Okay.
All right. Um
Okay. Next thing I need you to do is go
to your um Gmail. Make sure that you're
logged into the correct account. You
should be already have that because when
you did your um
when you made the bucket, you should
already be in the correct account by
default. I just want to make sure you
have that. Now, for the purpose of this
lab, I as your teacher logged out of all
other Gmail accounts because it makes my
life a lot easier uh to work in this
way. I'm just telling you. um you might
want to do like do a different browser
login and only use one account because
this next command is going to be kind of
a big one. All right. Um so if we go to
the repo.
Okay, this is the repo. Um
I have a lot of the how you're supposed
to do this. It's written here. Okay. So,
the first thing I need you to do is
authenticate your G-Cloud to your actual
G-Cloud, sorry, your G-Cloud client. I
need you to authenticate yourself
basically to the cloud. This is the
command right here.
I'm going to copy it.
And because I know that I've already
have my default value, I'm going to
paste this in here.
I'm going to make sure I do it
correctly.
There's some gunk on there. There you
go.
And it has default. Okay.
>> If if you successfully ran this
yesterday, particularly if I had to help
troubleshoot for a while and then we got
it to run, don't run it again.
>> This is made I'm doing this for the guys
who um haven't done this before. Now,
you notice I didn't look at anything. I
just said continue. Kept on going.
Some people were asking as if they had
we're going to have to pay 18 years of
trial support. Okay, it's um cloud
service. Chill out. It's okay. So now
what I've done is authenticated
uh my computer to G-Cloud and now I
don't need to use a JSON file in order
to run Terraform. This is a kind of a
big thing. All right. So,
next thing I need to do is actually get
a folder and get some Terraform into it.
Sounds good, doesn't it? Don't you think
so? Let's actually go run some
Terraform. So, what I'm going to do now
is I'm going to
go ahead and
go to I think go to my Terraform folder
and go to here, Seir one.
and go to week B. And not going to do
this one. Nope. I'm going to do
Terraform.
And
I'm going to call this one Terraform 2.
Going to make a new folder here. Call it
Terraform 2.
I'm doing this guy. I have I have to do
this as your teacher right now. If you
did this yesterday, you could follow
along, but I I have to do this again.
This just a part of the class. Okay. So,
I'm going to click open Terraform 2.
And now what I'm going to do is
um I'm just going to rightclick in the
folder and it says open Git Bash here.
And now I've done that. Follow also
follow what Aaron's saying. This is also
correct.
So, get bash opened. And now I'm just
going to type in here code
dot
code space dot and enter.
And now
what happened is my Visual Studio Code
opened up directly
where it's supposed to be. Okay.
Well, that works, too.
Actually,
to tell you the truth, you could
actually just do and double and
and it'll
>> Yeah, I I didn't want to get give them a
long one, but I I can put that in there.
>> Yeah, that's good. I like that.
>> Yeah. And then in my notes, I I show all
of that with screenshots. But, uh yeah,
let me rewrite.
>> Follow guys, follow Aaron's notes, too.
That's good. That's actually really
good. I like that. Good value add. Okay.
So,
next what I need you to do
is go back to my repo. I'm going to my
repo because I changed a lot of things
in here yesterday.
Go to Python.
Sorry. I'm going to go to the Terraform
part. Look into the chat. I'm typing. I
just put that into the chat. Um, this a
directory that I'm using. All right. So
let me give you a little bit of
information here. I did this
um I did this methodology in order to
help you guys learn and actually it
actually makes my life easier as a
teacher. Uh you need to follow this
methodology very precisely in the
beginning. If you do not, the likelihood
of you actually running Terraform
correctly is very low and we don't want
you running too much. We only want you
running a little bit and then you only
have you have we want to limit your
error messages so we can troubleshoot it
correctly. This is what we're doing in
the beginning for you as a student.
later on it won't be this way but for
now it is so that we can teach you how
to run Terraform. So all I can say is
please pay attention and follow this
methodology step by step.
All right
so the first file we're going to is zero
a zero authentication TF. What I'm going
to do here is okay, I want you to also
name your files exactly in the same way
that I'm naming my files. So I then I
know which file you're talking about.
Don't name it something else. You're
going to confuse me. Class will not be
fun. Okay.
So what I'm going to do here is going to
copy this. See how I'm doing this? I'm
just copying it. Copy. Going over here.
I have Terraform right here. This is my
Terraform 2 folder. See how this little
button right here says new file. Click
on it. It's going to give me the name of
it. It wants the name. And I paste that
in there. I press enter.
Now I have a new file named
0-authentication.tf.
And there's nothing inside of it, which
is fine. I don't want anything inside of
it right now. I just want to make sure
that I've gotten to this point. Okay.
So, everybody, please take a screenshot.
I'll make sure you guys are at this
point.
Please take a screenshot so I know that
you have the correct name and there's
nothing in there. I just want to make
sure. If you did this yesterday, you're
cool. This is mainly for the people who
are new or people who didn't get this
done yesterday. Okay. Good. Good. Kevin
Ernest,
good Ernest. Good.
Anybody else?
Nobody else? You guys all good?
Everybody else good on this cloud.
Okay, good.
Sean,
good. Okay, Vonyie.
Okay.
Okay, Sean. Good. Very good.
Anybody else?
Hope the rest of you are good. All
right? Because I don't want you going
back to this and you're not going to get
a one-on-one instruction on this one and
I don't want you abusing my admins. If
you're having problems with this and
you're not speaking up, go to your class
leader. But if you are having a problem
with this, you need to say something
now.
All right.
Okay.
Okay. Good.
All right. Okay. What I want you to do
is go back over to the repo.
Okay. I'm in here. This is zero
authentication.tf.
What the heck? All right. And I'm going
to copy this. Going to copy it. Raw.
Copy. Going to paste it in here.
Where's my paste? There it is. Okay. and
then save it. Make sure you save it.
Now, in here, there's some important
information. I need you guys to
understand what's going on here.
Okay.
Wow. You had COVID. Wow.
What? What are you doing,
RJB19? What are you doing?
We're not We're not even dealing with
that. That's from yesterday.
We're not even dealing with anything
like that right now. Notice I only have
one file here.
So, if you're dealing with something
from yesterday, you're reviewing it,
that's okay. But I'm not talking about
what I did yesterday at this time.
>> Richie, we're not going to be able to
fix your mic in class. So you can figure
that out on your own or maybe ask your
group, but we're not going to be able to
work on it in class.
>> All right.
>> Okay.
>> So, so Rich, yeah, keep yourself muted
because there's a lot of feedback.
>> You notice here it says project. It has
Thailand right here. That's because last
time I taught this last year, last
class, I would had a project named
Thailand. So this year I have a
different project and it's called seir
one. So I already have the see nice I
already have my project here. I'm going
to go over here and copy it.
I'm going to go to my terraform. Now
this is important. See how we have the
parenthesis here.
Keep the parenthesis. Okay. Don't mess
with that.
So I'm going to erase the Thailand
section.
>> Close. I'm just going to
paste that in there. Okay.
And then I'm going to save it.
Should be pretty easy. Easy peasy.
Okay.
What do you got, Christopher?
Okay, good.
James.
Okay, good. Go ahead and change, guys.
Go ahead and change your project name.
Yep. Make sure that you have the
parentheses in there. There shouldn't be
any error messages. So, so for example,
if I erase a parenthesis,
sorry, quotation mark. Sorry. If I erase
a quotation mark, see how I got red in
there immediately.
So, I put the quotation mark in there.
It comes back.
Can I expand this? I don't know.
This is it. Okay. So, go ahead and save
it. Now, if I make sure you save it, for
example, if I say PPP right there, and
then I erase it, see how see how there's
a white circle at the top in the tab?
That means I haven't saved it. So, go
ahead and save it. Boom. I'm good.
Okay.
Hello.
Okay,
there you go. James Kent, you're
definitely cloud engineer. That's right.
You're all dusty. Okay.
Has everybody done this?
Has anybody having a problem with this?
Say it now. I need you to say something
in the chat if you're having a problem
with this.
Because if you guys are all if if none
of you are having a problem with this,
this is an unusually competent group.
So, this is I'm like, yo, something's
up. Usually, I don't get that this many
guys having no problems this time.
All right. Okay. So, go to the top. See
how it says terminal up here?
Uh uh save. Just go to on Microsoft you
save you say control S. It's always
control S.
Okay. Or go to file here and then say
save right here. But control S is best
way.
>> Which is a good reminder everyone if you
don't have autosave on you do need to
save.
>> Okay. So, at the top here, it says
terminal. Open terminal.
Say new terminal. Make sure you're in
bash right here.
Now, I need to do make sure that you're
in the correct folder, but it's already
telling me I'm in the correct folder.
Documents, Terraform, Seir 1, Terraform
2. I already know I'm in there. Now, I'm
going to do an ls
to make sure that I have a Terraform
file. If you don't have a Terraform file
in your folder, Terraform will not
initialize.
Okay, I'm going to say this again. If
you don't have a Terraform F file in
your folder, then Terraform will not
initialize.
Okay,
this doesn't work.
Kind of like no. Well, I'm not going to
say that. Nope. Be good, Theo. Good. Be
good. Okay, now we need to do Terraform
and it first command for I have these
commands just so you know. Go back over
to here.
Again, this goes back to Terraform
basics. I have all the commands here.
Okay, so you can look at them if you
want to one by one. I'm going to go
ahead and copy this one.
Go and paste it here. Okay. Terraform in
it. Enter.
And yes, it initialized correctly.
Woohoo.
Yay. This means Terraform is installed.
I have a Terraform folder and it's
recognizing that I want to use
Terraform. So, this is good. Yay. Yay.
Yay. Yay. Yay. Yay. Okay. Next one.
Go over here.
Terraform validate. Copy it.
Go over here. Paste it in there.
Whoop. Didn't copy it, didn't I?
There you go.
Validate. It says the configuration is
correct.
All right. Next one. Terraform plan.
Copy.
There it is. Terraform plan. Enter.
There you go.
And then Terraform. Apply.
Copy.
Paste. Enter.
There it is. So, nothing was applied
because there wasn't anything to apply.
All I did here is check that it can
authenticate. That's it. That's the only
job. Can it authenticate to your G-Cloud
account? And it did authenticate. That's
all I wanted to do. Now, when it did
this, you notice that it created
something called a Terraform.tf
file and also created a terraform.lock.h
DH HDL file. And over here it also
created a secret folder. This is a
terapform folder with a license.ext
and this other provider information.
Okay. These files you do not touch.
Make this easy. These files you do not
touch.
All right?
I don't want to hear you saying, "Oh, I
touched it or I erased it." Any reason
that you have to erase these files,
you're wrong.
I'm not going to accept any reason. For
the purposes of the class, you need to
keep these.
In the office, you do not erase these
files whatsoever.
You do not. If you erase these files and
your manager finds out, consider
yourself fired.
You'll probably get a call from HR
within one hour and you'll be fired. you
what your action will be is an
endangerment to the company.
Okay? So, you're going to be gone. You
do not erase these. You take these very
seriously. And as Carlton says, there's
always one person every class on every
single class I've ever I've always had
this guy. Some person decides to erase
the file and I do not accept their
reason for erasing it. You're wrong.
There isn't, oh, well, I did it or I
accept. Nope. There's you're wrong.
Don't do that again. That's the wrong
course of action. Do not erase these.
Okay?
Don't even look at them. I don't want
you to do anything with them.
All right? Now, it has this apply as
complete right here. I want you to take
a screenshot of this
and put it into the chat so I know that
you did this.
Okay.
Are we happy?
Everybody show me that you're show me
your work.
Okay,
Kevin. Good.
John, good.
Martz.
Good.
Claude, wait. What? Too much
information, Claude. Okay, good. Guys,
just give me the Don't Don't do the
whole screen. For heaven's sakes, just
do one section. I If it gives me the
output at the bottom, I know you did the
rest of it correct,
James. Good.
Okay.
Sean
and
good Lynn.
Good Charles. Good, Earnest. Good. Okay.
All right. Uh, kind of not so many
people. Where are the rest of you?
Um, is is everybody doing this? Cuz I
got
47 people. I know I've got some class
admins in here, but I I I I thought I'd
get more screenshots and I'm not getting
uh the degree of screenshots I thought
I'd be getting. Tiqs doesn't have to do
this. Bash doesn't have to do this.
Carlton doesn't have to. I know they can
do this. Right.
All right. But the a lot of you in here,
I don't know if you can do this or not.
And you you're not doing this. This is
like a death sentence. If you're not if
you want to particip get that job,
I'll catch Oh, yata. What do you mean
yata? You're lost. If you're lost, why
aren't you saying something?
Okay. So, where you're lost at, yata,
you'll catch it on the replay. That
means you're going to drop out of the
class and make sure and make sure you
understand this.
>> I'm lost at uh I'm lost right after
authentication TF.
>> Okay. So, did you put the Did you save
the authentication TF in your folder?
>> Uh I'm on Mac. Uh
>> it doesn't matter. It's the same thing.
>> Don't see
what is it. Command save. Command S.
>> No, no, no. On your computer, you should
know how to save a file.
>> Do you Well, well, hold on. You have to
ask a question.
>> Do you know how to save a f a file on
your computer?
>> I see it.
>> Yeah, I figured out. Shift command S. I
just saved it.
>> I think it's just command S, but you
could also just go
>> shift command S.
>> Uh, okay. Command X. Shift command X
works for you. Where where are you lost
to now?
>> Uh what's the next step? Uh
>> okay.
>> Before Terraform Terraform validate
Terraform plan.
>> I need you to open your terraform. I
need you to open up your terminal.
>> Terminal.
>> See look look at my screen. Look see on
Visual Studio Code you got terminal at
the top.
>> Open your terminal.
Okay,
new terminal.
>> Okay,
>> I see it now.
>> Then then I need you to type in
Terraform init.
>> Oh, okay. Gotcha. That's where I missed
that. In it.
>> Okay.
>> Initialize. You want me to just
screenshot these, right?
>> Yes.
>> No problem. Okay.
Let me see. Terform in it. Terraform
validate.
screenshot.
Okay. Terraform and it it says
validating.
>> Okay. Yeah. Do the next one.
>> I mean initializing backing.
>> All right. Yeah. Great.
>> Terraform in it. Terraform validate.
Close that new terminal
form.
Got an error.
This configuration requires provide
registry
automatically by running. Okay.
Initialize back end. Okay.
Now run terraform plan.
This one terraform apply.
Okay.
Awesome.
Real African stars, you didn't run the
commands I gave in the chat. So, you
must have did this yesterday and you're
using the same configuration files. So,
uh you already have an existing backend.
So the commands are going to be
different for you.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> Sorry, Rob. What What would be the
solution for that? Uh did you post that
in the chat?
>> It's Aaron and No, just run uh Sorry
about that.
Yeah. Uh, real. We're only doing one
file right now.
>> Well, he I I'm inferring he's using the
files from yesterday. So, yeah,
>> you just need to run the commands and uh
or or or delete everything that's there
>> or start start up in a new folder. that.
Yeah, I mean like that's what my the
commands I posted would get you a new
folder. Uh or so I let me go find them.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Right, guys.
>> But also, you could scroll up in the
chat, too. I've
>> Yeah, scroll up in the chat. Get Get it
from there. You have to You really do
need to start this up in a new folder.
>> Okay.
If you're following along, you can do
what you're doing yesterday, but yeah.
>> So, I'm putting it in the chat right
now. So, you need to run that. It'll
open another instance of VS Code and
then you're going to have to make uh the
authentication file again and then, you
know, put the code in the authentication
file.
>> All right. Thank you.
Okay. All right.
Okay, guys. Pretty good. Now, we're
going to have another folder, another
file, right? So, this state file right
here, I don't want it to be here to be
honest or like I don't want to do all my
updated work on my computer. I actually
want to be in the cloud. The reason is
because these files, the state file
lock, all this stuff is very important,
contains secrets, and I don't
necessarily want it on my computer. I
prefer it to be in the cloud. So, what
I'm going to do is I'm going to get a
file to do that. Okay, I'm going to do
the backend configuration. So, I'm going
to go back over to here to my repo.
the top says Terraform. This one says
one-backend.tf.
Going to click on that.
This file name, I'm going to copy it.
Copy the name. Then I'm going to go back
over to here.
All right. Make sure
Terraform 2. It has new folder. New
file. Click on new file. Paste it in
there. Enter.
Now I have another file name. It's
one-backend.tf.
I'm going to go back over to here to the
repo.
And now I'm going to copy it.
Go ahead and paste it in here.
Okay.
So now
I have another file in here and it says
Terraform backend and it has talk about
compute disc. Let's be for later. We're
going to get to it though. All right.
Now right here it says there's a bucket
named Leo love TF. Do we want to use
that folder name? Do we want to use that
bucket name?
No, we don't because that's not the
bucket name that you have. So, I want
you to go back into your notepad and
copy. Well, did I do this again?
This is irritating.
Okay,
I want you to go to your notepad and
copy uh hold on. Where is I really I
hate Windows. Okay. Um, I want you to
copy the name of the bucket that you
made in G-Cloud before class started,
right before I did this Terraform. So,
mine is Ali TF. I'm going to copy that.
Don't worry, Alex. I erased the booty
level one. I'll get rid of that. I don't
feel like being so snarky today. All
right.
Go over here
and see the bucket name right here.
There's a line number seven. Going to
erase this. And remember the quotations
are there. The quotations are not
erased. See how the quotations are
there? See the quotations are there?
Going to paste that in there. And now
I'm going to save it. There I go. Okay.
All right.
We happy
everybody do this. You should have two
files. Zero authentication.tf tf and one
backend.tf.
If I go to my terminal, I go ls on my
terminal.
It says I have two files.
I have the zero.tf
and 1.tf. Don't even pay attention to
Terraform stake. Do not pay attention to
it. Don't do anything with it. Don't
touch it.
Treat it like kesha when you make a lot
of money. All right?
Don't touch it.
Right now, what I want you to do is take
a screenshot of this to make sure that
you're in the right position.
I need to make sure
that you're you're doing this right. I
saved it. How do I know I saved it?
There's no white circle up here in the
tab. Okay,
this shows me I've got two files here
and I got two files here. This is
important.
How do I create the cloud file again?
Yata, what do you mean by the cloud
file?
>> Excuse me. Um, you said
you would wanted the state file to go
onto the cloud.
>> Not do anything. No, do don't even talk
about that.
>> I haven't done anything. No, no. Okay.
Did you create this one backendtf?
>> Oh, okay. No, I did not
>> do that.
>> Yes, sir.
>> In the same
in the same uh
>> see how everything's same here. Okay.
Don't touch anything else. Okay.
Now, go over here. Copy the name.
Then I want you to go over to here,
say new file.
>> Ah, okay.
>> Then paste it in there.
Copy the name
here.
file. He say
okay
there.
Oh.
Okay,
beautiful.
Save.
So,
all right.
How do you get the state file? Am I
tripping? Never mind. I already have.
>> It's automatically created. Do not
touch.
>> Don't do anything with it.
>> Okay.
>> Don't look at it.
Okay.
All right. How about the rest of y'all?
We good?
Anybody have any questions?
Are you alive?
Are you doing this?
>> Well, if they if everyone's silent, then
uh seems that they're
>> they've mastered it.
>> Yep. They've mastered it and you will
not have any
you will have to circle the block 40
minutes later.
>> Well, Rob, he doesn't circle.
>> Um
Before
we move on, was there another step after
getting the the back end up
the backend.tf?
>> Interesting.
>> What
was there another step after getting the
backend TF into VS?
>> Okay. Did you copy the the code inside
the file? Yes, sir.
>> That's it.
>> Okay.
>> We did. So, you know, look, you're
looking into everything here. I didn't
do anything else. This is all I did.
>> That's a bit deceptive.
>> Yeah. Once once it's done, it seems
manageable. But before it sounds like
you're speaking a different language.
>> All I'm doing,
>> it is a different language.
>> All I'm doing is making a file and
naming it and copying something into it.
>> That's it. Watch this.
>> Your name is Yata. Watch.
New file. Yata
loves
leiso.
py. Enter.
I just made a Python file.
I can go in here and say yata married
Leiso last year.
then control S.
It's not a different language. It's copy
and paste.
That's all we're doing right now is
copying and pasting
and typing.
This is fourth grade level. No more than
that. Okay?
This is all we're doing. I'm not making
you code. The code is already provided.
All right?
Making sure you pay attention to this. I
understand this is what's going on.
All right.
All right. Good. Next.
Okay.
So, I'm going to go over here. I'm going
to do terraform it again.
That's right. Provider
back in. Yeah. Okay. Okay. Terraform
that's because I need to initialize the
back end.
Okay. And then do Terraform
validate.
Terraform
plan.
And it says here add one. And now
Terraform apply.
Okay. And it says yes. Want to add? Say
yes.
Wait a minute. Tio.
>> What?
>> I've got uh plan add four. You've got to
add one.
Can you
>> That means you're adding more.
>> Yep. is having.
>> It's okay if you're if you're running
more files and you're there's more
objects in there, but right now I only
have one object.
>> Okay.
Okay.
>> Yeah, we only have one resource right
now.
>> Yeah, it's um he's planning to add
graphana disc.
>> Uh the network may Oh, okay. Okay. Okay.
It's because I
>> It's just the persistent disc right now.
>> Yeah, I I know why. Because I I followed
the file and so I I did the VPC one.
That's why I've got more. Okay.
>> We're not the VPC.
>> Yeah, it's my fault. So you
>> Oh, he he's in a different time zone, so
he's ahead.
>> Oh,
yes.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Okay,
>> that was good. Okay, that was good. All
right. All right. That's right. All
right.
I'm sorry. Could you repeat the last
step again?
>> All you're doing is these commands
again.
Type them in.
>> That's all you're doing. Paste.
Type them into your trouble.
>> Okay. Try. All right. Now, what I want
you to do is go to your bucket.
um to your to your bucket in
your in G-Cloud.
So, I'm going to go here. You know, I
see I have my Aligni.tf. Sorry, my
sorry, my align it, right? I click on
it. And now there's a new folder in here
called Terraform. And inside the
Terraform, there's a state. And inside
the state, there's something called
default.tf.
Don't play with this, but it's
successful. Internet Correct. Claude,
what's up?
>> You didn't run the ADC command.
>> I'm getting um errors. Um it says um
initialize in the back end and it says
>> in the beginning of the class, he gave
you a G-Cloud command. It says like off
uh default credential login, something
like that.
>> I see. Okay.
>> Got to run that,
>> right? All right.
Hold on. Let me
let me get to you.
>> Oh, it's right there.
>> Oh, okay. You got it. All right.
>> No, no, no. I It's No, I meant I I
didn't see it on your screen. I wasn't
uh
It's not in the chat. I'll put it.
>> Okay. I got it.
>> No.
John, you're not authenticated to your
uh account.
>> John might have a different issue. I I
want to see the error in context. Let's
see a screenshot.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> And is that the Gmail you use for your
GCP account? John,
also run G-Cloud O list and show us a
screenshot of what comes out of that. Or
here, I guess I'll put
G-Cloud
list.
Which John is this?
John Williams.
>> Okay.
Okay. And show me a screenshot of the
command I put child. Did you Is that the
>> No, that's not. So
>> Oh,
did you get the bucket name wrong?
you know, I I created the bucket and I
put it in the
in the uh backend.tf.
>> Show me a screenshot of your back
backend code block. So, like where you
have your where it says backend and it
has the curly braces and then all of the
arguments. Show me a screenshot of that.
Yeah, that's right.
>> Well, it's not that I don't think it's
right because there wasn't a syntax
error. This is an API error. So, it's a
>> is that bucket
>> odd
>> the bucket name is it right? So uh you
assuming G-Cloud works for you, can you
run G-Cloud storage buckets list
this
I'll put it in the chat
or you could go to your console
Because if the resource doesn't exist,
then you'll get a permissions error,
too.
>> Yeah, I got a I got an error. Let me uh
send you the uh screenshot.
>> No, no, that command should work
regardless. It should work.
You guys are going to have to work on
getting G-Cloud to work. You have to
have it working for class.
Yeah, it's mission critical.
I like this too. I want this.
>> Yeah, let's see.
>> So, run G-Cloud off login like it tells
you to.
Yeah, it's sending me to uh I have a
couple of emails. Maybe I authenticate
with the wrong email. Let me try the uh
>> Oh, you said that was the one you were
using. So, I I you're going to be the
only one who knows that.
>> Okay.
Okay, let me
yeah, I went and ran uh
the uh G-Cloud storage buckets list
again and it's it's the same error. I
did it with a different email and uh
same same issue.
>> Well, it should you you shouldn't be
changing emails.
>> Me, let me run this again.
You need to go to your console, figure
out what Gmail you're using to use G
GCP.
No, no. This This is a This looks like
he's either not logged in properly to
G-Cloud or something, but at this point,
it seems like he doesn't know what Gmail
he uses.
>> Okay, I see which which I see which
email I'm logged in with. A and that use
that email to go to cloud storage and
um click on create a bucket and and see
if it lets you get into that menu or
actually it should if it lets you see
your buckets that means that you at
least have uh the list permission. So
that that would mean it's the right
account. So I
>> I have one bucket that I created. I'm
going to create a new bucket and see
what no
>> Okay.
>> What is the email
that you're using right now in the
console?
>> Uh yeah, John Con uh Gmail.
>> John,
let me hold on. Let me
I'll just uh
up this. No, that didn't let me put it.
>> Yeah. So, that doesn't match the email
that you had initialized
with.
Yeah, that doesn't match the email.
>> Okay.
>> No, because the initial error you gave
us.
>> Yeah.
>> At uh four 7 minutes ago, it says error
403. Uh wrath
uvjgmail.com
does not have storage.objects.list
access, which is true because that's not
the Gmail you use for your GCP account.
Uh-huh.
>> So, the error totally makes sense
because you've logged into G-Cloud with
a Gmail that's not what you use. So, you
need to reinitialize G-Cloud with and
then once you're once the SSO happens
and it takes you to the web browser, you
need to choose the right Gmail account.
So, run G-Cloud and
do the whole process again.
>> Hold on. Go ahead. share your screen.
>> Yeah, give me
and if ever anyone else while he pulls
this up wants to follow along. So, seven
minutes ago he gave us an error. This is
this type of error from Terraform. It
it's not coming from Terraform itself.
This is coming from the what requests
Terraform sends to GCP. It's an API
error in it. It's saying he doesn't have
permission to do things and it says that
he's signed in as a certain Gmail and
that he doesn't have permissions to
access his bucket. So if we look and
then I had him run G-Cloud off list,
that's going to show which Gmails he's
signed into G-Cloud with. Chose that
same G-Cloud, but then when he goes to
the GCP console, he sees it's using a
different Gmail. So we have to get them
to match.
So open up uh so make get bash a little
bigger. I I can't really read it.
No. Can Can you just increase the font?
I don't know how to do that since
I've never done it.
Just
let me see if control plus works here.
Hold on.
>> Yeah, control plus works.
>> Control scroll.
>> Control plus.
>> Just go to the terminal and just use
your fingers and expand it.
>> There we go.
>> Okay. So, run G-Cloud and it
All right. So you go to two for we need
to create a new configuration.
So just name it whatever you want.
Okay. So, press one.
Okay. Choose the project ID you use
J.
You can set a default region and zone or
not. It's up to you.
>> Uh, that's what
>> No, no, no. That's not what it's asking.
Says yes or no. Y or in.
>> Do you want to set one or not?
>> Okay.
Okay. So, you didn't set one because you
didn't choose a number, but
>> I chose eight,
>> did you?
>> Yeah.
>> You don't.
>> Perfect. So now run G-Cloud off list.
>> I have I have two emails in there. I I
guess I need to get rid of one.
>> We We're going to do uh
G-Cloud
config
set
account
then a space and then the email you
want.
and enter.
>> Okay. Wait. So, if that's the one you
want, we're okay. Hit control C. That
one's active.
All right. Run G-Cloud info. Let's make
sure it's all set up right.
That's the right project ID and email.
>> Yes.
>> All right. So now you need to reset your
ADCs. So the command that Theo gave you,
do you have that? Um,
the G-Cloud off default credentials
login one.
>> G-Cloud default.
>> Oh, Was it in the uh
in the repository you sent?
>> Yeah.
>> Was it in in here?
>> Yeah, it's it's in the notes
in the repo. I think it's under
Terraform basics or something.
Okay.
Okay. And
now just to make sure G-Cloud works,
it's authenticated, go to Git Bash,
>> okay,
>> and run G-Cloud storage buckets list.
Let's see if this works.
Okay. So, disabled access your account.
Uh, cool. So, go to VS Code.
Um,
run which Terraform command were you
trying to run? Anit probably.
>> Uh, yeah. Okay,
there you go. Okay.
Is it apply now or
which one? Uh
>> yeah, I don't know if they got it they
got to that step. Uh I mean it won't
hurt to do it right now.
Okay.
>> Looks like it's working.
>> It is working. You knew it was working
after Terraform and it because at that
point it has to authenticate to GCP.
>> Cool. Hey, thank thanks for helping me,
man.
>> No problem.
Okay.
All right, Sean, what you got?
>> Hello. Uh, I don't have the uh files in
my new button.
>> You did a different bucket name or
something like that. But if you do the
correct bucket, it will go up there.
It's the way Terraform is designed.
So, if you didn't get any error messages
or something like that, then either you
didn't do a refresh or you're not
looking at it correctly, something like
that.
So,
Sean, did it create the persistent disc?
>> The persistent disc. Uh where would I be
able to find that?
>> Uh under compute engine in the console.
Uh more
engine console.
>> Hold on.
>> Actually I could I could just start
giving commands for everyone so we don't
have to go to the console.
There it is.
>> You could run that command as well,
assuming you you can use G-Cloud, but uh
I I forget GCP's global with their
commands or most things.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. So,
we'll try that.
and then show us a screenshot of what it
gives you.
>> My desk is there.
>> Yay. Good job, Theo.
>> I'm just I'm showing the classes. It
should look like that's all.
Oh, wait a second.
Now, which of the uh
console should it be in?
>> Under compute engine and then under
disks.
>> Compute engine under disk.
And that's from the uh let's see.
Oh, wait a second. This
listing more commands I need to put in
there.
Yo,
so I'm just going to put that in
the check. I'm just going to in the
terraform. I'm just going to put that in
there.
um to remind people that they can always
do it. I I I have the list of at the
AWS. I have the commands, but I didn't
do it in GCP. So, I'll make sure I get
this done for next week.
>> I'm still just waiting on my computer to
catch up.
>> Are you not on a computer?
I am but uh for whatever reason it's
taking a while to get to the computer
engine the disc like you were asking
it
>> okay so I just made this
>> the the the CLI command should be
instantaneous
for that
>> really basic
Chewbacca how you doing how you doing
Okay,
good.
>> He mentioned that I had zero items from
the uh command line, the G-Cloud compute
disc list.
>> All right. Can you share your screen
real quick?
Yep.
>> Okay. Hold on.
Can you all see my screen?
>> Yep.
>> Okay.
>> Well, you're right there. So, you don't
have any discs.
>> See, it says no rows to display.
>> No rows.
>> So, open VS Code.
If I need to make it bigger, uh, just
let me know.
>> I already So, I already see the problem.
Uh, clo close the restart update in the
corner of VS Code and maximize VS Code.
>> Yeah, you're not in the right folder.
So run the command ls
he is in the right folder but for some
reason but this seems to be happening
with for people I don't know why they're
making files inside the terraform folder
but
>> you explicitly told them not to open it
but so what you need to do is
up here in the uh VS Code uh explorer.
You need to grab that file and then drag
it down here.
Okay. Now, if you run ls again, you'll
see the difference.
So now it sees that file.
Let's see. So let me go. Should I
refresh my uh G-Cloud?
>> No, you have to run the Terraform
commands.
>> Okay.
So, you see before it didn't say this.
It wouldn't have said this.
So now move to the next command.
And then now see this is a difference
from last time. Do you see where it says
it's going to add something?
>> Yes.
>> Last time it wouldn't have said that
either. So now we know it's actually
going to make something for us, which is
the persistent disc.
>> Okay, that makes sense.
All right.
Go ahead and go to the console and
refresh it.
There's a refresh button in the console.
There it is.
Okay. Thank you.
>> Mhm.
All
right, guys.
All right. All the Rudy clicks.
I like that. All right, guys. Let's go
to the next one. All right, everybody
get this dish to work. We good here?
Anybody have any questions?
We got enough time to do VPC. Let's do
one more. Okay, we want to do one more.
Yes. No. Put a one in the chat if we
want to do one more Terraform file.
>> Let's do it.
>> Put a two in the chat. give up and you
just want to do cometia and live with
Kesha for the rest of your life. Come
on. Kha needs some loving.
Come on. I want to I don't see no too.
How many of you guys want to pay child
support for Kha?
No, you guys don't want to pay no child
support for Kishha.
She do need some loving.
That's what the bear is for.
Oh, holding that to you. Oh, I ain't
loving no Kishha. Oh, screw that. I can
snuggle up with my dogs. Okay.
Okay. So, going to do VPC next. We're
going going back over to here. Remember
in the repo? You guys can see my screen,
right? We good? Okay. So, I'm going to
VPC
and I'm copying this name. Let me copy
it.
And now I'm going to go over to here.
Make sure you're in the correct folder
again. I'm at Terraform here. Terraform
2.
New file. And paste that in there.
And I now have a file named 2-vp.tf.
All right.
Next, go over here. I'm going to copy.
I'm going do a raw file copy
and go and paste this in there. Okay.
All right. So now we have a VPC and the
name of this VPC is going to be main.
All right. Now, if I go over to
go over to compute real quick and type
in the type over here, type in VPC
networks.
I have my the name of my
VPCs right now are birthday VPC,
default, and elite. And inside of Elite,
I have subnets.
Remember this Netherlands, Sao Paulo,
Vincent Leiso Booty, and Vincent Leiso
honeymoon. I remember that. That was
fun. Remember when we did this subnets?
Vincent was so fun. Okay. Anyway, I hate
you, Theo.
So, now we're going to make a VPC named
Mate. Okay. Let's have some fun. So, put
this in here. I'm going to put See, hold
on.
Let's go ahead make this a little
bigger.
Okay,
I need to save it. See how they have
that white the white circle there? I
need to save it. I'll go ahead and save
that. And now we'll just go right down
here. I'm just going to go ahead and say
uh Terraform
validate
and then Terraform
plan
and has three to add. Good.
Now, what do I do next?
What's next?
Terraform apply.
>> Good.
Say yes.
Oh, I forgotten.
Actually, I have to say yes. Yep.
I do that so many times.
Now
you notice what did you notice about my
methodology?
Did I just do three Terraform files at
one time?
No, I did one file at a time. I did
zero, made sure it worked. I did zero
and one, made sure it worked. I did zero
and two, made sure it worked. Okay,
that's how I did it step by step.
When you're doing Terraform, you need to
do this step by step, particularly in
the beginning. If you do all of these
files at one time, you're probably going
to get you're going to probably screw
up. Then we have issues and you're going
to get discouraged. You're probably
going to drop out of the class. I've
seen this happen I don't know how many
times.
So, this is on you. You need to do these
step by step. This is how I learned
Terraform personally. When I was
originally doing it,
>> I made I just did one object at a time,
one resource at a time, and I just put
it through in the office. This is very
much how we do it. Okay.
So
yeah, you did something something's up
with you did. Uh yeah, I'll I'll have
somebody else stick with you. Okay, so I
have this I ran through. Sorry, did
that. Now remember, look at this. I have
three VPCs. I have birthday VPC, default
VPC, and elite VPC. I'm going to
refresh.
And I have something called main. I have
main VPC. Wow.
I didn't have to go through and make a
VPC on my own. It made a VPC for me.
Isn't that nice?
Is that fun? We like that.
Oh, there you go.
Yay. Isn't that great?
So, do you want to do it this way or
do you just want to do click ops or kha?
Kisha, you could do ka ops. You guys
want to do key shops? I I I like key
ops. I
It does resource transfer for 18 years.
>> Yeah, just just close the computer, shut
the meeting down, and uh head outside.
You'll be fine.
>> We can just work at Waffle House.
That's That's advanced.
>> That's advanced Kha.
That's advanced. You got to start with
Chuck-E-Cheese where her where her uh
her her young king is having a birthday
party. So, make sure to go pay extra for
the pizzas over there.
Give her young king the the father he
deserves.
Okay. All right. So, everybody get this
now.
Okay. If you guys I want you to take a
screenshot of your subnet of your VPC
and put into the chat. So, take see how
here VPC networks. Going to put that in
there. Capture
and put in there. Please take a
screenshot so I know you did it.
Kevin. Oh, Kevin, good job.
William, good job.
Sean,
good job.
Martz,
good job,
Mr. Alex. Good. Jack
Rob Bob. There you go.
Verest. Very good. Look, look at all
these people who want cloud jobs. I want
cloud job, please.
I want cloud job. Cloud. Go to dark
mode.
Jazz. Tres. Trey.
Trey. RW. Good job, James.
James already has a subnet. James, did
you do a subnet already?
Did you go to the next file and already
apply it? Because you shouldn't have a
subnet in there,
right?
Okay, you can do that though. I don't
care. John, good job.
I like being a shock trooper. All right,
guys. How is everybody?
Okay, so this is as far as we're going
today in class. Next week, we'll
continue
Uh
yeah, yata. I don't know what's going
on. You I I don't know what you're doing
there.
You're you're going off into another
world. I don't know what you're doing.
It you you were things were running with
you and then suddenly you just
you went off someplace else. Um Yata, I
want you to stay on and talk to the
admins and and clear that up. All right.
because you're if if you continue on
that you're not going to be able to
terraform
that cloud job is not going to happen.
Okay.
All right.
So in order to do a tear down all you do
is do terraform
destroy.
say yes.
>> Do we remove the bucket we created for
the class also?
>> No.
Do not touch.
Okay. So, we have four
objects. Okay. Now, notice this. See my
VPC. Going to refresh.
Main VPC disappeared. Oh no.
>> What do I need to do if I want to
redeploy main VPC?
>> Yeah, if I'm apply
>> Yeah. Don't we just um go back on VS
Code and initialize and apply everything
again?
>> Well, you don't you don't have to
initialize. Just apply. Watch.
>> Okay.
>> Terrible. Apply. I only have to run
initialize when you change the provider
or terraform code blocks.
>> Gotcha.
>> Yeah, it's really beginning.
>> See,
it redeployed.
I'm going to go back over to here.
Wow, main VPC is back. Oh,
what if I want to destroy? What do I do?
Terraform destroy.
>> There you go. So, I go ahead and just
All I do is do up arrow twice. Up,
terapform, destroy. Boom.
Yes. See how easy that is, guys?
Isn't that fun?
Also, you might show them running
Terraform apply twice in a row won't
change anything.
>> Well, true. True.
>> To demonstrate the idio potency of it.
>> Okay, I'll do that.
Yeah, we love our uh we love our Waffle
House. I should walk there. No, I'm not
going to walk there. Well, it it is
between my house and uh my gym. I can go
there. I might do leg day today. Um
destroy complete. Resources for
destroyed. Very good. Now, what I want
to do is um
let's do apply again.
So if I do apply
say yes.
Okay. Now I'm going to do apply again.
Okay.
see no changes, nothing happens.
All right.
Now, one little thing I'm going to teach
you guys real quick. See, Bane is right
there.
What do you do
if you want to change the name of
something?
So, let's say I have Maine right here,
right?
I want to change this to Waffle House.
What do you do? Okay, a lot of you guys
would do destroy, terraform, destroy.
You shouldn't do that. This is what you
just do. Just come over to here and say
Waffle House.
>> Well, that that's not the VPC name.
computer network.
>> You changed the label, the local label.
>> I just do it all one time.
I I don't want have to think.
Let's keep it together. Okay. Want to
see here? I haven't saved it. Right.
Save.
Okay.
So
now what I'm going to do is I'm going to
go to plan
opt out.
So see here it has one to add and one to
destroy.
So currently there's a VPC named main.
The VPC named Maine needs to be
destroyed and then a new one is going to
be created named Waffle House.
But all I did was change the name here.
That's it.
So I'm going to go ahead and do apply.
Yes.
No, you're correct, Aaron. The reason
why I do it both is because I'll get
confused over time. I'll get tired. And
if I don't see this twice,
the likelihood of me making an error is
massive. So, I just put it on there
twice.
But you don't have to. You're right.
>> Yeah. If it but if it were a a mutable
attribute for the resource, renaming the
local label would nec necessitate it
getting recreated entirely, even though
it didn't have to be.
>> Right. Right. Right.
>> But I don't think you can rename a VPC.
So in this case, it's immutable.
So it makes sense for it to re recreate
it entirely.
>> Yeah. Just do it. Just recreate it. Make
life easy.
Okay.
All right.
So, see how that worked? Wasn't that
cool?
All right. So, let's go over here real
quick to over here. Let's go to refresh.
And I now have a VPC and a Waffle House.
Are we happy?
Yeah, we do. Good job. Yay. Waffle
House. We have a reason. Yay. Okay,
good. All right.
Okay, guys. That's it for today. Make
sure you do a terraform destroy at the
end. Let's do this real quick. There it
is. Destroy.
Okay,
that's it. You're done for today.
We'll see you guys next week, guys. Um,
very few of you submitted your UDMI
homework from last time. You guys need
to do this. So,
I need to be rather strict on your
homeworks. So, I do want to have that
for next week. Okay. You want to put
that back into the group? Make sure you
guys do that.
>> Wait, you demi homeworks? Are we
supposed to send an image of the
completed uh section?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Send it to me
>> in GitHub or just just the image.
>> They should probably put it in GitHub
and then send it to me. GitHub. They
don't well mo the new students won't
know get
>> but they can also submit it to their
group leaders and their group leaders
can just give you a summary too unless
you want to review it yourself.
>> Oh is group leader or to me either one.
I actually I prefer you send it to group
leaders.
>> As long as they're saying you guys are
doing it I can check with them. Um but
as long as you guys are saying you guys
are doing it we're good.
>> All right.
And remember, ju just like a building
code, Theo's homework is the bare
minimum.
Your groups should hopefully be
progressing through the Udemy faster or
you independently
Okay guys, thank you. Thank you all.
Bonui.
>> Yeah. Enjoy. Hey.
>> Yep.
>> And
uh I'm going to give
>> Have a gonna make Aaron host.
>> All right. Have a good night.
>> Yep. I'm going to drop. Go ahead and
work a little bit more with Aaron if you
want to and I will see you guys later.
>> All right. Raise your hands if you have
an issue.
Carlton.
>> Yeah, we have those issue with the U.
>> Yeah.
>> No JSON authentication stuff.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. So,
>> let's uh take a look.
>> Give me one second.
Yeah, Brandon, when uh I don't think
Jules is recording today, but Bash is
here. So, yeah, they'll as long as Bash
or Jules is here, they'll end up on one
of the playlists.
All right. Should I do just my um bash
terminal or my SDK?
Uh,
I mean G-Cloud works in Git Bash for
you, right?
>> Yeah, I can do G-Cloud and get
>> Yeah, let's just use just get bash for
now.
>> Okay.
To share your screen
now.
You see my screen to be terminal.
>> I see the I see get bash. So
>> okay.
>> Uh can you Yeah. Incre increase the font
like one or two times.
There you go. That's perfect. Uh all
right.
So let's reproduce the original error.
That was the the
command line
argument
G-Cloud
off
uh let's say application hyphen default
base login
and then enter.
>> I did.
>> Okay. Yeah. Yeah. So,
all right.
My other page brings up my Gmail
accounts.
Log into.
>> Yeah. Can you Can we see that?
>> Can you see this?
>> I only see Git Bash.
>> Doesn't look like you're sharing the
screen.
One second.
I do full stand.
>> I'll just have to back and forth with
this.
>> Can you see it?
>> Uh, I can see the web browser now. and
uh
>> ch and so yeah the is it the doc.cloud
Cloud Ops one.
>> Yeah.
>> Then that's definitely what you're using
in the console.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Click on it.
Select all.
No, no, no, no. Select all.
Continue.
Forgot this before.
And what does Gipash say?
Get back.
>> All right. So
I'm going to give you another command.
Uh
one sec.
All right, it's in the chat.
Yeah. Okay. Looks like you have the
token now.
>> Okay. So then I'm good, right?
>> Yep.
>> Okay.
>> I mean, you could give it a test run in
terraform.
>> I'll need to undo my JSON key.
>> Yeah, you can. Yeah, just remove the
credentials argument.
Do you want me to stop sharing while I
do this?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
All right.
>> This one of those tickets where you'd
get it sent back and they'd be like
unable to reproduce error.
Who's next?
>> Um, I'm working with Bash Cloud. Um, he
just he just stepped out, but I know not
everybody here
got what they needed.
Let's see.
Yeah, Richie, you're probably going to
want to work on your mic like before
class.
Mr. Pierre, just share your screen since
nobody
seems like they need help.
Dude. Okay,
>> Bash, you can keep you can keep helping
it helping him. He's sharing his screen.
>> He had to use the bathroom.
>> I just I'm back. I'm back.
>> You guys hear me?
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right. All right. Cool. Uh yeah, I
just want you to run the ply.
Actually, you run the previous commands,
right?
>> LS, right? Right.
uh LSD was just to make sure that you're
in the correct uh folder um which you
seem to be. So just run uh just run and
apply or run a plan
Terraform plan. Actually you don't even
need to need to do that. I think I've
already got you up to this stage. Just
run terraform apply. Terraform apply.
Just right.
Yes. Just type in yes or lower case.
Nothing else will do.
this for
this project services Thailand.
All right. So, which region did you
have you set your default region or
anything like that? Have you set any of
your
uh I don't know what you mean.
>> Um, all right. Just type in G-Cloud info
in
any term.
>> All right. Is that Is that email does
that ring a bell?
>> Yep.
>> Is that correct? Is that the only one
that you have set up?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Your G-Clo. Yeah.
>> Yes, sir. go up to the arrow again.
Didn't see the arrow. I need to read the
arrow
that Okay. You want to see that part?
>> Yeah. If you could also just um just
maximize your
>> Oh, yes. Let me just close this section.
How do Let's do this. Is that better?
>> Yeah, much better.
>> Platform. The error was up here, right?
And then we did Yes.
>> Yeah. Just just leave it.
>> Permission denied.
>> 43
mission denied. Access.
You might have
>> might be some sort of IM error, I'm
guessing.
>> H what error?
>> No,
>> he didn't he didn't configure his
provider block correctly.
>> Oh, okay. All right. Uh go back to uh
zero authentication.tf.
>> This one. Okay.
Was I supposed to change this t project
Thailand? Yeah.
>> What am I supposed to do with this?
>> Is that your Is that your project? Is
that the correct project?
>> Oh, the project. Let me Yeah, it's over
here. Sorry, I can't share both screens.
This is the
No, the project name is supposed to be
Oh, I remember now. Okay.
Keep the quotations.
Uh the the quotations are just to they
just indicate it's a string. Um as I'm
aware, you just want the bit in between
the quotations deleted. Keep the
quotations
>> like that.
>> Yeah, that's correct. Yeah. And then
save it.
Okay,
>> this will do. Um, another thing is I've
noticed that your backend.tf is not
saved as well. So, just make sure that's
saved too. Is that saved or I'm not
looking at Yeah, save that.
>> Yeah, it's saved. Um, I guess for play
time. I think you could just control.
>> What are you pressing
>> when you're saving?
>> Command shift S.
>> It's weird. It doesn't do that for me.
>> It's He's doing save as.
>> Okay. All right.
>> Oh, for some reason it doesn't work when
I just do command S. Um, so but do I
change the bucket name to my bucket
name?
>> Yes. Oh, here. Let's do this. Go to file
at the top of your screen.
>> Okay. File up here.
>> And then you see where it says save. You
can see the shortcut. It says command S.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. I think you were using command
shift S. Is that what you said?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. Just use command S. Um.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. All right. You've done that.
Great. Saved. Right. You need to init
this again. You need to initialize it
again. So you need to run a Terraform
init.
Should I start a new terminal?
>> No. This is probably part of the reason
why you're having all these issues is
that you've got like 51 terminals open
there. Uh and you're getting confused.
You previously did um just use the same
terminal. I would say
>> yeah, you can close all of these
terminal instances.
Okay. What do you mean like close like
hit the trash?
>> You see the trash can? Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, that's it.
>> Yeah,
all right. Run. Uh,
but this bucket doesn't Are you sure
this bucket exists? The bucket you have
defined there?
There are commands that you can run for
this second.
>> Sorry.
>> Okay.
>> Did you hear me or what?
>> You said there are commands that you can
run for this.
>> I meant in the uh in the terminal, but
you can actually check it in the console
as well. while I was searching for the
command
>> G-Cloud storage buckets list.
>> Yeah, that's the one I was looking for.
Yeah.
>> But yeah, just uh it's not called uh
yeah um just go to Google Cloud Storage.
Just type in Google Cloud Storage at the
top
>> in the uh terminal.
>> Yeah. in in the cloud in the console.
Yeah.
>> Hello.
>> Yeah.
>> Google, I'm sorry. It's Google Cloud.
What? What am I running?
>> Uh within the Google Cloud Console.
>> Wow, I'm getting crazy lag spikes. This
is ridiculous.
Yeah, I'm getting a bit of lag as well.
Is the lag me or is it
>> I don't know.
>> Uh,
I'm lagging so I think it's me.
>> Um, yeah. All right. You know,
>> me. Do you mean is screen share is
lagging? Cuz it does
>> Yes.
>> seem blocky.
>> Yeah, it's like it's like dark blocks.
Yep.
>> On the screen. So, I mean, uh
>> yeah, my my computer's not even working
right now,
>> right?
>> It's ridiculous.
>> That's probably the reason why. But I
would say you can run this. You can go
within the console. If you go to the GCP
console, you can do that or G-Cloud
storage buckets list. You can complete
whichever you prefer. I just want to
see.
>> Oh, yeah. Check storage. Okay. I
remember now.
Gosh, man. I can't even see my
screen.
is bro. What the I
hate Mac, bro. I don't get it. I don't
get the craze.
>> All right.
>> It's fine. We're having technical
issues.
>> Holy
>> Just remain calm.
just crashed.
>> All right. Uh, I mean
>> this is
>> just do that what I just told you to do
in it when when you can. Uh, I'm just
going to paste in the chat.
>> Can you say it one more time? What do
you want me to do?
>> Uh, G-Cloud storage buckets list. Just
type that in the uh in your terminal in
VS Code.
>> Okay. Storage
storage.
Hey, Richie. Bucket list.
Okay.
What the Hold up. Storage.
Pull up a couple different things.
Created bucket. Yeah. Oh, it's Gracie
underscorebucket. That's what
Okay.
>> Yeah. I can't see what's coming up on
your screen there.
>> Yeah. Um
I trust that you seem to be okay.
pull over the the Google Chrome window
that I have GCP up on, but it just
started lagging like crazy.
>> Uh, do the best.
>> But my bucket name was wrong.
>> Your bucket name was wrong. All right,
save that out.
>> Okay.
What the
Bro, what?
All right, we're over. Command S.
>> Yeah, command S. And then run that last
command again. The init.
>> Okay.
>> Terraform in it.
>> Oh, this start makes sense.
this thing
state was found in the newly configured
GCS.
>> All right. You've got um you've got a
local state, so I'm guessing you need to
migrate it. Um let's see find
Oh, actually
to stick to the new GCS.
Yeah. Enter. Yes. We could just do that
instant.
>> Do you want to copy this?
>> Yes. State.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Just enter the word. Yes. And
that's it.
>> Now, okay,
>> that's it.
>> Ter or or Okay, it worked.
>> It worked. But now you need to complete
your task. So complete by
>> I'm just testing. Yes, Richie, we can
hear you.
>> Thank you. I'm out.
>> All right.
>> Well, if you need help, Richie, stay
stay here for a minute.
>> So, what were the last couple steps I
needed to to take? Uh,
>> you just want to run apply. I think
that's lost.
>> Okay.
Terraform apply. And then
Okay.
Yes. Just Yes.
>> Okay.
This is a 2022 Mac 2. Like, I cannot
believe it's this slow.
might be that you're just your hard disk
is too full. So it could be that or you
could be having
>> okay
>> could be a number of different issues to
be honest. But more time it's never
really the hardware that is the
constraint. It's usually the way we're
using it. So just bear that in mind.
>> I got too many tabs open. I got you.
Apply complete. Uh, four resources
added. Nice. It didn't say that before.
>> Yeah, you're good. Um, so yeah, you
should be fine now. You could double
check all the resources that you expect
should be reflected within the console.
So you should be able to find that on on
the GCP console. So if you go back to
the console, you should be able to see
all your
>> So after this, you're going to need to
run a destroy.
>> How do I check?
>> Go back to the console.
>> I'm on it. I'm sorry. I can't drag it
over. I wish I could share both screen.
>> Uh then don't worry about it too much.
But yeah, you should be able to if you
go into your console,
>> these resources are going to actually
exist. They exist somewhat. So you're
going to see the resources that you've
just deployed. So I just wanted that
little
>> moment to click, but it's not
necessarily
um I mean I I pulled up my project.
Okay, no problem. No problem. Is there
anything else that you need me to take
care of?
>> Uh to be honest,
you know what? Just run the um this
shell commands that you can run to save
your resources. So um one of them is the
uh the dis.
All right. Uh,
it'll be GC G-Cloud, right? G-Cloud
>> and then space
>> compute
>> compute.
>> Yeah. And then space
disks
with a K.
>> Oh, with a K.
>> Yeah. And then space and then list.
>> List.
>> Yeah. So, you should have this resource.
You have this one. I mean, I know you've
got your resources, but I just wanted to
show you that.
>> Oh,
>> you see? So, this is what you created.
>> Graphana disc.
>> Yeah. So, this is a resource that
exists. You have to be aware that your
resources, they actually are somewhere
and you are going to be charged for them
for the use of them. So, you can't just
leave them running forever.
You have to take them down as and when
you need to take them down. So now
you're going to run the last command
which is going to be terraform destroy.
>> Okay.
>> Which is just going to illustrate
exactly how you do that.
>> So run terraform destroy now.
>> Yeah. And also before you finish that
command uh space. No just that was fine.
That was fine. space
and then hyphen
auto.
>> Uh, don't have them use flags yet.
>> No. Okay. All right. Don't don't worry
about it's fine fact. Just uh terform
destroy and then just run enter.
All right. It's going to ask you to
confirm it
and you're going to need to type in yes
again.
Okay.
So, we're doing this because we can't
leave
we can't leave this thing open.
>> Gro unless you're a billionaire. I mean
like you know if you if you got it like
that then just keep your resources up
forever. Uh I mean if you you these the
whole point of this the whole point of
cloud is so that you can use the
resources as and when you buy them and
that when you don't need them cuz this
is not on prem that's always on you know
this is like flexible. So these are
resources that you put on the ephemeable
resources and this is part of the
workflow is that once you no longer
require your resources you can delete
them you can destroy them and the moment
you carry out this you will stop getting
charged for them by Google. So right now
I'm guessing you're on a free
>> yeah right now I'm guessing you're free
right now I'm guessing you're on a free
tier but there may be times in the
future when you're not. Especially if
you're working for other people and you
never want to leave resources unattended
or unsupervised.
>> Yeah,
>> that's one of the leading causes of of
blog in terms of cloud fun. But all
right, that's about it really, man. Um
>> Okay, I can stop sharing.
>> Yeah. Unless
>> awesome. Thank you.
>> No, I think I'm good.
>> All right. Much appreciated.
Whoever needs help, step up.
>> Rich, you still there? Oh, I think he's
gone.
>> I guess not.
>> Yeah,
>> look.
>> You would be surprised. You'll be
surprised that what we've just told you
is very like it's spread and bar. It
sounds very simple, but there's a lot of
organizations out there that they are
actually their bills are going out of,
you know, control simply because of the
fact that they have resources that
nobody's got kept track of. Uh, yeah.
So, just be aware.
>> I know how to copy and paste in a
different language. Appreciate you.
>> Like, I'm getting confused. It's just
copy and paste.
>> It seems like it right now. Yeah. But it
doesn't really matter about that. It's
mostly about the mechanics of what
you're doing. So you need to understand
the process of what you're putting into
play. Um it doesn't matter the fact that
you wrote that file or you didn't write
that far at the moment. It's kind of
irrelevant. It's mostly do you know how
to actually use these films and what do
they do? The implications of that.
That's really what you're into right
now.
>> Thank you for your help.
All good.
>> All right. Anybody else need help before
I close this out?
All righty then. I'll see you guys next
week.
>> Thank you, Erin. Yep.