This meeting is being recorded
>> 10 times a day to people.
Uh, next installs. Everyone should have
GCP account fully configured. They
should have G-Cloud initialized. They
should have VS Code with the extensions.
All of this stuff should be done. If it
isn't, I don't know how you're in Zoom
right now because you shouldn't be in
Zion.
Uh, next, sharing stuff. So, sharing
invite links, sharing passcodes, sharing
Zoom links, don't do any of that.
You're liable to get banned. And that'll
be Theo doing the banning. Uh, after
that, homework. So, Theo did list off
some Udemy sections, which I had
mentioned those sections earlier this
week, too. Uh, hope you guys are doing
those cuz just showing up to class isn't
enough. group leaders will start setting
a pace for going through the UNME and
PCA prep as well.
Um, finally, I saw some weird Zoom
names. Hopefully those guys fixed them.
I should be able to connect your Zoom
name to your Facebook profile name.
Uh if if not then
you know it's confusing like
uh just looking at it right now I don't
know if that Bob Okay Bob just fixed his
perfect and then
I don't know who that is
going down
let's see
just John I don't really know who that
is
um
let's see who's this Robbo guy
>> random.
>> All right, that looks pretty good for
the Zoom names.
So that's everything everything I had to
yap about.
I guess questions. If you have questions
about the announcements or
something with groups,
I got a question. So, for the
deliverables, I did everything for the
install. I forgot to screenshot those
and put those inside my group. How will
I be able to get back to that?
>> So, your deliverables aren't done.
>> No, like I did everything like the this
was on the sheet, whatever the case may
be. I just didn't screenshot it and put
inside the group chat.
Well, let's check something because if
you didn't have your installs done,
>> so I did all the installs if that's what
you're talking about.
>> But you you've been in the group for
three years.
>> So you can't join you can't join Zion
twice, right?
>> Right. So I got everything.
>> So did you read the pinned message in
the group chat?
Yes, exactly.
>> Okay. So, then you skipped the section
where it said prior students don't have
to submit deliverables.
>> Okay.
>> Right.
>> Answer my question. Okay.
>> You guys got to read the pin message at
least once. It hasn't changed in like a
week.
I get if it maybe if it was changing
every day, you guys be it's kind of hard
to keep up.
But that's been in there for like since
the beginning of the group chat.
I already forgot how to say your name.
Estress.
>> Yes. Estras.
>> Got it. What's up
>> about the groups and the signing sheet?
Where can I find it?
You find it in Zion.
>> In Zion,
>> we put everything important in the
feature tab,
>> which is also the end message.
Sorry, I'm not I'm not laughing at you
guys. I'm laughing at my admits. That's
all.
>> Okay. I mean, I'm sorry. We're not
Denil. [ __ ]
>> No, no, no. I'm laughing what Julian
said about Serge and uh and uh the
Indians. That was a funny comment.
What are they going?
>> I mean I I mean that hopefully as time
marches on that's going to be the way
that uh someone graduates from the class
if
>> if they can take if they can make an
Indian not have a job
by superiority of knowing what they're
doing then maybe that's a badge of
honor. How many Indian scalps can you
get out of the office? I would say I
want
Oh, Theo. No, Theo. The Theo. No, you're
not gonna say that. No.
>> What? You want Indian Scouts for for
your next birthday? Okay.
>> No. No. That's
God. I'm so bad.
I wanted
>> Bash. It's not I I don't I don't blame
him. I mean, Theo does, you know, Theo
may want some curry chicken once in a
while. He likes curry. He's from Japan.
He's Japanese inside. He wants curry.
Curry here.
>> He wants curry. Right. Right. So, we
need to bring in more Indian scouts for
more curry.
>> No, no, no. What I was thinking was,
you know, like what is it? Like every
time you hear a bell, an angel catch his
wings.
>> Yes. What I wanted was
>> um at the graduation ceremony at at the
conclave
uh we'd have an effigy of an Indian and
every time one of us gets graduates the
effigy gets teabagged by Chewbacca.
>> Oh god.
>> I know that was pretty pretty gracious.
>> Let's not let's not go Indiana Jones.
Okay, we don't need to do that.
I was thinking that I was thinko
if they take video of that.
>> Yeah, let's let's let's not Okay, you
you you you could you could you can do
that. You you can host a private
session, a breakout session where you
can host a breakout session for that.
Okay.
>> All right.
So, I just got done with a big ride and
I still have not used my car, but that I
thought the ride was going to be a lot
easier. It was not. That That was a
vicious hill.
Oh god, that was a hard hill. So, I'm a
little messed up right now. Anyway,
uh what are we going to do with you guys
today? We want to do class. You guys
sure you want to do class?
>> No. Well, they maybe just want they
maybe just they just want to hang out
with you, Dio. Just want to part way.
>> Yeah, just Yeah, just just hang out.
>> Chat about where where you want to move
next, you know, cuz I know you I know
you're just spinning the globe and
picking a random country at this point.
So maybe that maybe that's what they
want to talk about.
>> Um what what do I want next? I don't
know.
>> You want you want chicken k. That's what
you want.
I do I do want chicken cut. Um
okay guys, so welcome to Saturday class.
Um so one of the things as Aaron was
talking about if you look at the repo
you'll see there's homework right here.
MD. Okay. I still haven't changed this.
So I screwed this one up. So this is the
UDMI and this is the homework and this
is the UDMI and this is the homework for
it as well. Okay. I need to go edit it.
So, make sure you guys um do your
homework and submit it.
Well done.
Did you say I sound like your dad?
Uhhill both ways. No, no, no, no. It was
uphill one way, but that uphill is epic.
It's an epic uphill.
So, I'm dead.
I don't even know why I did that. Oh, I
didn't I didn't want to spend anybody on
gas.
Hold on.
>> How much is gas?
>> I don't know. I haven't bought it since
the war started.
>> So,
rich man doesn't want to buy gas.
>> No. Well, it I don't want to buy It's I
got cardio, right? I mean, it's pretty
big cardio. do it. So, got that done.
It's
uh Okay. So, anyway, this is your
homework right here. So, just make sure
you guys do it. Okay. Um
let's go over here to uh Google. Okay.
And we'll go ahead and talk about
uh
what they call a VPC. And a VPC is what
we call a virtual private cloud. And
that's going to be your network that you
can use within the cloud. Okay. So, in
order to get there, hold on. Is
everybody open up your consoles? I need
you to open up your console. This this
is a pretty intensive thing you guys
need to be doing right here. Okay.
Wait for you guys to open your consoles
up.
Uh,
right.
All right,
everybody. Good. All right.
All right. So,
I want you to do is going to go go to
the search bar and type in VPC networks
or just VPC. That's fine. Click on VPC
right here is on drop down and you will
go to your uh VPC area. I'm going to go
ahead and turn Oh, there's a six rule in
here. Interesting. Okay.
Ah, now I know how this works. Okay. So
I'll add that that this is where you
have you create your VPC or your virtual
network
um for you to do your own computing or
to do your work in. When you did your VM
last for the last two weeks, you were
using the default VPC which is right
here. And basically in the office you
are not supposed to be using a a virtual
sorry you're not supposed to use your
default VPC. It's very poor planning and
it's just not what you're supposed to
do. So, if you go over here and then you
go, this is your default. I'm just
showing you what default is, right? You
click on default and then I go to
subnets.
This shows you the default subnets uh
that are being used everywhere uh within
GCP. Now, these are default. These come
for free for you uh to use within your
account. But uh in the office we never
use the default just not the way it is.
But I just want to say that they they
are there. Okay. And they are the same
for all accounts.
All right. So we need to talk about how
we plan a network and how we design one.
Okay. This is kind of an important thing
to do. So let's do this real quick.
Okay.
Um, what I need you to do is to pull up
RFC
1918.
Okay.
So, how many people in the class have
never heard of RFC 1918 before?
Put a one in the chat if you've never
heard of this before.
DeAndre, you were in class yesterday.
You heard of RFC 1918.
Come on.
All right. So, RFC1918 specifies
what a public
network is versus a private network. A
private network is designated or
reserved by these network spaces.
A private network cannot be routed on
the internet. A public network can be
right. Um so if we go
if you go pull up um what is it? Go
ahead and pull up one of your terminals
real quick. And I'm going put in here IP
config.
I do my IP config right here.
You will see that my local address for
my computer
is
well my network is 192 16886
and my host IP address is 230.
So my network address is 192 16886
and my host address is 230
and this fits right here within the
private address space which is specified
by RFC1 1918. So here it is. All right.
Now, all of you at home, if you guys do
your IP config, you should all have um
an IP address which is in either one of
these. It's either in 10, you either
have what I call a 10net, a 172 net, or
a 192 net. So, let's do this real quick.
And I want you guys to tell me how many
of you guys have a 10 net. If you have a
10 net, put a one in the chat.
Red Bull. I like to have that right now.
Good. In fact, why don't you quickly
write down your 10 net that you have
into the class, okay? So, everybody can
see what you have.
If you guys have a 172n net, put a two
in the chat and then write down your
your uh IP address so people can see it.
And if you have a 192 net,
put a three in the chat and paste it in
there. So I put mine in there. Three. Go
and paste it.
So there it is. Three. And I put mine in
theirs as well. Okay, good.
See? So, you see how that works
everybody? It it it works the same way.
All right. Now, what you will notice
with this is particularly for the threes
is that 192 168 is the same. The third
octet, which is right here, is different
for most of the people. So, Charles,
it's one, for me, it's 86. For Jason,
it's one. Okay. For Bob, it's zero. Poor
design. Toré, one. Bad design again.
Kevin Wilcox is four. Okay, good. Aaron
Briley is 50. Okay. Vanny is one. Poor
design. All right. My little comment.
That's my snark comment. All right. Um,
so you can see what see they're doing.
You see a lot of you guys have a zero
and one. That's actually a poor design
by your um
by your uh internet provider. They
should give you a different number
because 0 and one are the two most
common networks used by 192 168 and
they're very easy to guess and so
therefore they're they're easier to
attack from the outside.
All right. Now, if I do trace route real
quick, hold on to your trace route. I
always get this right wrong.
Okay, let's do it this way.
Okay, if I do a trade route real quick,
I get to see which public address I'm
using.
So, I don't own it, but it's there. So
it gets translated.
So what you're saying here is
this is 192 16886.1.
Say 86.1. That's my router in my house.
Almost always a.1 is a local router.
Almost always not always but damn almost
always. All right.
Okay. And what we have here is you have
my local house and then you have a local
point of presence and that's also
private. So that's an ISP operating. And
then something's going on here that
Google doesn't want me to know about.
And then it gets to this one right here,
MCI Global Fiber.
Google Fiber.net. So I have 123 255
22464.
that is a publicly routable
um internet or router uh at an ISP.
So that's the first point which I
actually have public access. So
basically there is what we call NAT
translation. I'm going through a double
that. So I have well no I'm not going
through double that.
Maybe I am. No. No. Shouldn't be doing
that. Uh, they could. No. Yeah, double
that.
So, I'm being natted to this IP address
and then this IP address being natted to
this IP address, which is wild. But it's
a way for them to conserve IP addresses
and they just simply put do not have
enough IP addresses. So let's just we
use NAT in order to this network address
translation in order to uh increase the
number of IP addresses that we have
available. Now you guys might be
thinking why am I talking about this?
It's because when you make um your
network
in here, your VPC,
it has to adhere to the rules in RFC
um 24, sorry, in RFC 1918.
It must adhere. You cannot play around
with this. You can't say I'm going to do
something different. No, that fails.
This this is the way it is. This is it's
internationally this is an international
standard. You have to comply with this.
So if you notice um here with the
default VPCs in uh in GCP
all of them comply but these are all 10
nets and they all comply with this RFC1
1918. Okay. Now, I'm going to give you a
sample one that you can do that you can
use. Uh, but my big thing I'm going to
tell it to you right now is when you
make your own uh VPC um is you need to
plan your VPC first about how we're
going to do how it's going to work and
secondly you need to um
you need to read this RFC and understand
it forwards and backwards. It is mission
critical for you to read this. Okay, I'm
not joking. You really need to read
this. Please, for the love of God,
please read this. Um, it's a all of
these everything in this is a legitimate
question. And if they ask you, for
example, um, please tell you how please
how did you use RFC1 1918 within your
VPC,
which is a very legitimate question on
an interview. Um, you need to have an
answer immediately and you should be
able you should be able to knock that
off like on the top of your head. If you
have any like uh or well maybe it was
kind of like this failure means you
don't understand 1918
right when I started doing networking
when I started working in computers this
was um I started doing help desk in when
I knew help desk in 98 and RFC in 1918
was
2000 when I started using it and this is
February 1996
and it has this has not changed at all.
This this standard has has been there
ever since. It's it's not going away.
Okay. Um any questions before I continue
or is everybody good? Let's keep on
going.
We good. Anybody have questions?
Are you are you all live there? I got 53
people in the class.
>> Yeah. 45 of them are dead.
>> Got a pulse.
>> All right, great. Oo, I like that. Vader
Alexander filter. Good. Okay, so what
I'm going to do today is
I'm going to say my main network is 192
168. Today I'm going to put this as
100.
And then I'm going to say Salpollo
is 192.168
um 120.0/24.
I'm going to say Tokyo is
192.168.140.024.
So I'm going to make um
three subnets. All right. new three
subnets today. Now, think of it how I
did this. I want you to see how I did
this real quick. Main network is Iowa.
Oh, yeah. Quick. Who says Iowa's going
to get educated by the Ali today?
Who put a one if I was going to get
educated by the by line? I just want to
know how many people agree.
I and I
all right you people who didn't get one,
you get extra homework.
Sorry, you didn't answer quick enough.
I'm I'm listening to this. Everybody
above TIQS and above gets spared. The
rest of you don't.
Tad, you get triple homework. You're
getting an Armageddon in personal
tomorrow.
>> I'm deleting it. I'm deleting it.
>> Oh, no. No. I saw that. I already saw
that. I Well, there are the Elite 8. Oh,
no. No. There's no forgiveness for this.
No mercy, no forgiveness.
If my all I get to the sweet the the
final four. Oh my god, I will be so
drunk next week. I'll be at the bars.
Oh, it'll be so good. Anyway,
all right. So, these are my subnets that
I'm going to use. You notice that I have
these planned already and they're on my
notepad right now.
This is because I need to transfer them
over and so I need to have these planned
before I start. I don't just do this
willy-nilly. I actually have this
planned before I start the
configuration. Okay.
You sound like y in two years we'll have
dreadlocks in Brazil. I I might
I I don't know if I'll dread I'll be I
don't know.
I'll say this. Brazilian women are
winning. But if I go to Japan, I told
you guys yesterday I got the job offer
for Japan and I gave a verbal
acceptance.
So if I did go back to Japan for two or
three years, I know where I would go
date. It would it would be very simple.
I would date in Kawasaki and Yokohama.
I would be on the prowl in those areas,
right? Why? Because there are Brazilian
Japanese there.
Okay.
All right. So we're going to go ahead.
I'm going to go to this VPC section.
And I'm going to rotate here the top
one.
Okay. And it says create VPC. Click on
that.
And uh here we go. Uh the name of this
is going to be
it has to be lowerase.
Elite 8. Okay.
Okay. Description can describe it
everything you want. Okay.
And come down here and it says want a
new subnet. Yeah. Okay. Make a new
subnet.
So I'm going to call this one align.
has to be lowercase
and description.
So, Ali
owning Iowa
in Iowa.
There you go. And the region, get this
region right. Make sure you get this
region right. I'm going to put this
region in Iowa. See this? Choosing that.
Okay, I got a subnet. I'm calling it Ali
and I'm I'm putting it in US Central
one, Iowa. Okay.
Now,
so it's IP version 4. Not touching
anything there. Okay. And it says, hey,
what's this what's this range? You
notice I already have the range ready.
All I need to do is go over here. I got
my range, right? Copy it.
Copy.
Paste it in there. Paste.
Got my refresh rate. Okay.
Next one. Private Google access on.
Okay. And now I'm going to add No, I'm
not. I'm not going to do that. I'm going
to add a subnet right here. Add subnet.
I'm going to call this one
S Paulo.
Okay.
description
Sao Paulo my second home
and the region is going to be hu I
wonder what's going to put Sa Paulo now
IP stack IP version 4 again we're not
touching that and what's the range we'll
go over here salo I have a range going
and click on this copy
paste Okay. Oh. Oh, don't put words in
there.
Okay.
Okay. Make sure no white space. Uh,
that's actually kind of an important
thing.
White space. Okay. All right. Same
Private Google access on. All right.
Now, I'm adding one more submit. Tokyo.
Okay. Hold up. Make sure I didn't put
any capitals. Okay, no capitals. Region
is going to be Tokyo.
Uh, we'll find Tokyo real quick. Where's
Tokyo? There it is. Asia, Northeast One.
And it's IP range. Got the IP range
right here. Copy it.
Paste.
Okay.
Private Google access on. There we go.
There we go. All right.
So, I have now three subnets.
Okay. Before I continue,
does anybody have any questions? We're
just at the subnets so far. I want to
know if you guys have any questions
about the subnets.
>> Yes. Can you redo the first one? Can you
go over the first one again? It's the
same as the other ones,
but you don't have to do it this way.
You know, you can name it anything you
want. You can put it in any region you
want. You can do what you want with
this. This you are free.
It's the same thing three times.
>> Okay. Got it. Got it.
Why would they be specific to my
machine, Vincent?
Why? What? What is spec What is about my
machine?
Why? Okay, Vincent, I got to do this to
you. No, I gotta I gotta educate you on
this one. Okay. Name Vincent
Leiso
Booty.
There we go. description
subnet
where
Vincent
celebrates
his love and devotion.
Te vot to Leis
booty.
Okay.
Sorry, Vincent. YOU ASKED A QUESTION.
I'm going to make you learn right now.
That's the only way cuz now you will
never ask that question again. Okay.
Region. What's a good reason for this?
Give me a good reason for this, guys.
Dallas. So, I put it in Dallas, LA.
Oh, Vegas. Mumbai. You want Mumbai? I
like that. Okay. Mubai. Putting your ass
in Mumbai. Okay. So, there we go. Mubai.
All right.
And I'm going to go over here.
Vincent
Leo love
192.168.69.024.
There we go. Oh, Theo is so bad. Theo,
stop. Go back to therapy. No. No. Okay,
so I'm going to put this over here. IP
range is right there. Paste. Now we put
the 69 there because we know that's a
favorite thing for Vincent and Leiso. So
there, that's a range. We all know what
that's going on there. And now we go
private access. Yeah. Yep. Yeah, that's
odd. That's it. We got it. Okay. So now
we have four We have four
subnets. All right. We got Iowa, we have
Sa Paulo, we have Tokyo, and we have the
special Vincent Leiso lover subnet in
Mumbai.
Okay,
follow the tray. Follow the
instructions.
Okay,
now follow the error. It's giving you
it's it's telling you it's wrong.
Okay. Now, next one. So, the firewall
rules
have here select all.
I want you to select all of these. And
this is going to allow custom, allow
ICMP, it's allow RDP, allow SSH. Okay.
We will allow other ones later on. She's
coming for Vincent. Yeah, she wants to
ride it. I know. There we go.
Okay.
So now we have regional dynamic routing
mode.
Uh here let's do dynamic routing mode
today. Let's do global.
Uh that's fine. Should work. Okay. So
remember before we make a VPC, what do
we do?
What's the tradition?
>> Pray.
>> We pray. Yeah, we always pray. Please
God, please let this work.
>> Okay,
there we go. Delete eight.
Vincent is not will never let me will
never forgive me for what I've done.
Why did you do this? I just went to
class. I wanted to do was there. I
thought your computer was connected to
the cloud and it dictated GCP global
routing.
I learned it the hard way.
Yep. What you learned today?
>> Yeah.
>> Is there a reason we changed the routing
mode?
Um, so now I can it's dynamic. So then I
can make a piece I can make a VM in
multiple regions and then ping each
other
it it's only affects cloud routers.
>> I said global it's I mean I don't want
to do regional
>> it doesn't affect them though either
way.
>> Yeah.
All right. So, what I want you to do is,
okay, go here real quick. Going look at
Elite 8. We'll look at my subnets. And I
have a list of my subnets. Okay. So, I
got Ali, S. Paulo, Tokyo, and Vincent
Leiso, Booty. I have four subnetss.
Okay, this is going to be good. Now
let's make an EC2
in um a custom EC2 sorry make a custom V
VM in our custom subnets. Okay, I'm
going to do right now just make open up
a new tab. The reason I'm open up a new
tab is just so I'm have this as my
reference in case I need it.
There you go. And I'm go here to create
a VM.
Okay.
Now, the first one I'm going to do is
call this
Vincent
Leiso
Lover
Lane. Okay, there we go. And I'm going
to put this one into Mumbai.
Okay,
let's go down here. Nook. There we go.
And any zone, I don't care. And oh, 30.
Oh, who cares? All right. This is all I
need to do here. OS storage, nothing.
Data protection, no backups.
Networking. Networking is important. Pay
attention to networking here. So, I need
to tell it where to go. All right. So,
listen up to this. This is an important
thing. First, allow HTTP traffic. Allow
that. All right.
Now
we go down here. Says network
interfaces.
See how we have a default.
Click on it and it has default network.
We don't want that. Click out of that
and click on your VPC which my VPC on
this one is elite 8 and see how it goes
automatically to the subnet le Vincent
Leiso booty. Okay. It's automatic,
right? kind of nice. Why was it
automatic? Because when I started over
here in machine configuration, I chose
Asia South one and Asia south one is
Mumbai and that has a subnet of Vincent
Leiso Booty. Okay. So because it has
that that subnet automatically appeared
and populated when I chose my own VPC
which is Elite 8. Okay.
Oh, Vincent, you will totally learn VPC
now. So will all the students, thank you
for being a perfect learning instrument.
You're really I'm sure everyone is
learning this right now. You're this is
this is great. I'm just telling you.
Thank Thank you, Vincent.
Oh, goodness.
I I see somebody like knocking at my
front door. It's my therapist. Neo, you
shouldn't do that. Yeah, I should.
Sorry.
Are they learning this at Black?
I don't think so. Okay. Now, the rest
here, I'm not going to do anything here
for networking. That's it. That's all I
need to do. I want you to go here down
to advanced.
Advanced, we have we need the startup
script, right? So, I need to go back to
GitHub.
And in GitHub, I'm going to go to my
repo. I'm go to weekly lessons
week a user scripts. And that go to
super a.sh.
And going to copy this. Just for anybody
who having problems with the navigation.
Here you go with the navigation.
Copy it.
Return over here and paste it here.
Okay.
And now you click here and say create.
Wow. What's the name of my VM?
Can somebody tell me what the name of my
VM is?
>> I want make sure you guys make sure to
reinforce it. What? What do you say,
DeAndre?
>> Oh, Vincent Lizo Lover.
>> Okay, good.
And what subnet is it in?
>> What's the IP of the subnet?
As a
>> What is it? It's right there on the
screen.
DeAndre, you need to know this.
If you don't know this, you don't this
is this is critical for you to
understand this. Okay? You cannot
not know this. You have to know this.
Okay. Um Christopher Alexander, what is
the internal or internal network for
this um subnet?
Christopher Alexander.
>> No, no, not 34. Where you getting the 34
from? I used
>> You're asking for the cider range for
the subnet, right?
>> Yeah.
If you can't, if you don't know what a
sire range is, put a three in the chat.
DeAndre, you've done this more than
once.
How do you make a subnet
without know not know without knowing a
cider range?
Well, at least they're Andres. Okay, you
guys need to get this because if you're
if you don't know this, you're saying
you're not making a subnet. That's what
that's what you're actually saying.
>> This is keep bringing it up that
especially if you're new to it. Like I
have the list of videos of background
networking knowledge that you really
should watch that would explain all of
this with nice pretty animations.
>> Yeah,
>> it's better than anyone can do in class.
this internal IP 192 16869.
This is your cider range. It's right
here on the screen. So, I make sure you
guys get this because if you don't get
this, you're going to have trouble. So,
that's your network. Okay? And I I had I
wrote it out here in the beginning. So,
that not only is your your cider well
your cider range actually is a little
different, but that is your internal
network that you're using right here.
It's right there stated 192 168 69.
All right.
And that is in compliance with RFC19
18. It's all together. Now, how do we
know this is the correct one? We did it
right.
First thing we're going to do is connect
here to SSH. Make sure we got things
done correctly.
Yep. Authorize.
Okay, good. Now I want to get some Oh, I
don't I was not trying to do that. What
just happened? Okay, let's go get this
right here. Oh, no. Don't want that.
There we go. I need some commands on
here real quick. Wait, where's my zoom?
Okay, so I need to go over here. Go back
to zoom. So I go back to my uh what is
it? My repo. I'm going to go to week a
text. I'm going to go down here and see
it has curl s local h localhost age. Go
ahead and copy that.
Go over here.
Paste it.
Ah, good. It gives me information that I
have that I need. So, I know this is
really working. It's not a joke. All
right. So, this is this is working
correctly.
Oh, what I want you to want to do next
is
we're going to go ahead and this
external IP. Copy it.
I'm going to say here http col/ slash
paste.
Now, this tells me
that I'm in the criteria.
All right. project project sir instance
Vincent leiso loverl lane and the
internal IP address is 192 16869.2
perfect
I know it's in the correct one okay go
ahead and copy this and you guys can put
this into the chat and we can work on
this and see make sure we correct each
other's work
There we go. Lisa Vero BEEN BIRTHDAY. A
no yeah you be you be tripping. Huh.
Okay. There we go.
Okay. There we go. I like it.
All right.
There we go.
Fight back. Shoot. I didn't go fight
back. You lost. All right,
there you go. There. Yeah. Yeah, you're
tr you're trying. Uh, Ernst,
there we go. Sovereign man. There we go.
Okay,
Mr. A.
Very good. Vincent
Leiso Lover. There we go.
Joe
Valkyrie and internal. There we go. Very
good, Joe.
Jock.
There we go. Instance, Iowa. Oh, you're
so nice, Jock. There you go.
All right, John.
There we go. Okay, I like this. Put in
Yokohama. There we go. Next one. Ted.
Good. Camp.
Good.
Kevin Wilcox.
Good. Okay. Charles Keys.
Good.
Okay. See, some of you guys got it. All
right.
All right. So, what we're going to do
now is make another uh VM. All right.
So, create instance right here.
This one I'm going to call it S Paulo.
Uh, what's a good one?
Uh, special.
The region I'm going to choose for this
is going to be Sao Paulo.
All right.
We'll put this over here.
Okay.
$40. Yep, that's right. Yeah, this is
kind of the problem I'm kind of seeing
right now with Brazil.
It it looks great, but it's more
expensive. Doesn't make sense, but it's
more expensive. All right. OS and
storage, nothing. Data protection, no
backups, networking.
Going to do this again. Allow HTTP
traffic. Okay. Scroll down.
Network interface.
Network is not default.
Put it into elite 8. You notice that my
SA Paulo
custom subnet appeared automatically
because I configured it from the
beginning.
Right?
What is my network range for Salo?
Put it into the chat. What is my network
range for Salo?
Nope.
Give me my number
or give me my subnet value.
What's my subnet value?
Uh,
you're getting there. That's close.
Yeah, I I can see how you say that. That
way, that's actually not correct.
You're close there, Gregory. You got one
of the octets correct. I need I need uh
three more.
So, that's right. So, Josh Ox is
correct. 1921 168.1
120. that is the subnet value. You can
go further and say024.
So all you have to do is say the
entirety of it and that's what it is.
That's your subnet value. Uh Aaron,
>> so if I were to answer that, I would
kind of answer it differently. Maybe it
makes more sense to the new guys is he's
asking like this range. So
you guys will have to look that you know
study this later but this is like a
shortcut notation here the slash24.
Another way to say this is this is a
range of IP addresses from 192.168.120.0
all the way through 192.168.120.255.
>> Yeah. Although technically
192.168.120.0.1.254.255
are reserved, but that's basically what
it said.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah.
>> So, okay.
There we go. So, I just want to make
sure you guys understand this. The
subnet is there. Right there. Okay.
and go down here and
go to advanced. Same thing. Go back to
my repo.
Copy it.
Start script. Paste.
Okay. And now create.
So what is the name of my first VM?
What is the name of my first VM?
>> Vis.
>> Good. What is the name of my second
VM?
>> Sound special.
>> Special.
>> S Paulo Special. What is the name of my
first VM again?
>> Vincent Lizo Lover Lane.
>> Oh, that's good. What is the IP address,
the internal IP address of the first VM?
>> Uh 192.168.69.2.
>> Good.
I like that. Here you go. Oh, Vincent, I
was you're you're helping them learn so
much today. Thank you for being a
teacher's assistant today. Thank you,
Vincent. They're learning a lot. They're
learning a lot. Everybody's learning
today. Especially you, Vincent.
Langy boy, what was your question?
>> Oh, um I was beyond lost. Okay. After I
make the the VPC network, what was the
next step?
>> The keep on following. That's it. You
might have to go.
>> Yeah, you it looks like you didn't make
the subnets. So, I can't go back to that
right now.
>> Sorry.
>> All right.
>> I'll show you how to make another I'll
put another subnet in.
Okay. So, first thing I'm going to do
for Salpollo special, I'm going to go
over here, copy it to the clipboard.
All right. And
click on SSH. Make sure SSH is working.
Yes. Authorize
SSH works. Good. Next, I'm going to take
go over here. http col/ slash paste.
Wait a minute. What the hell?
Did I There's no way. I know. I clicked
it.
Hold on.
>> You put a startup script in.
>> No. Uh, let me
>> go to the very bottom. It'll show if
there's a startup script.
>> No, I need to do networking.
>> Yeah, you you did HTTP traffic.
>> It has the network tag.
>> There it is right there. Yep. Uh
>> go to the go to the very bottom under
metadata.
So, no startup script. See if
>> I pasted. Oh, okay. You just have empty
line. Oh, you copied the wrong thing.
That's not a startup script at all. Oh
my god. I did do that, didn't I? Oh
[ __ ] I have to do this again. Okay,
hold on. I'll finish this real quick.
>> But that's good for the students to see.
We It didn't work. Checked. We have HTTP
access. Do we have startup script?
>> Hey,
this is machine image. I don't want to
machine instances. Uh create instance
to
the solo.
>> Yeah, I did. I thought I was in the
right place.
Yeah.
Okay.
I missed in here working. Oh, that's
right.
There it is. Okay.
And
let's try
Uh,
>> that's good for them to see though your
internal IP.
>> Yeah.
>> You see the pattern here, guys?
>> 2.3
it increases.
What? I can make a few of these.
Okay. Authorize.
That's it. Your demand.
Okay. Copy this one.
There it goes. Okay. So, here it is. VPC
Elite 8 instance Apollo 2 and I'm in the
correct region. Okay.
The other region was Mumbai that's where
Vincent which remember
the other reason this is Asia South one
right it's a Mumbai and the name of that
one what's the name of the first
instance again I forgot
what is the name of the first instance
can somebody tell me
>> ah there you go thank you I I had a hard
time reading that I having a hard time.
Okay. And what is the IP the internal IP
address for the first one?
>> 192.168.69.2.
>> Good. What is the name of the second VM?
>> 192.168.12.
>> No. What is the name of the second VM?
>> Oh, S. Paulo 2.
>> Good. Where is it located?
Where in which region?
>> South America.
>> America. East.
>> Okay. So remember, South America is a
continent.
So you'd either need to name the actual
city or go right for the zone. But
everybody would just say Sa Paulo. It's
located in Sao Paulo.
Make sure you get the say the word
correctly. Sao Paulo. If you say South
America East one, nobody will know what
you're talking about. It's like if I say
US Central one, nobody knows what that
is. Just say Iowa. Everybody knows what
Iowa is. Okay. Salo 2 VM's
IP address. The internal IV press is
what?
1 192.168.1
12.3.
>> Yep. Yep. Um, you don't say I have to
say point say dot
or if you really want to just say go
quick 192 168 123.
That's it.
Because if you say it a lot, you're
saying dot dot dot dot dot point point.
It gets redundant. You get tired of
saying it. So you just say the numbers.
Everybody knows what you're talking
about.
Okay, there we go. Got that there.
There you go. Yep. Cord fields. Okay, so
what we got here,
Mr. A? We got
good
Mr. K.
Good.
Okay. Vincent
S. Paul special. Good.
I'm surprised they didn't say like save
me or something. Kevin Wilcox.
Good. I like this.
Okay. William gave.
Okay. Good. Okay.
Okay. Good. Let's go. Rob. No. Bob.
Lori. I like the [ __ ] I've been flying
in Floria.
I should go to Floripa.
Marry a poor spent a lot of money to
marry a poor Brazilian.
Uh, good. But, uh, Ted, good. All right.
Now, guys, I want you to use the status
group. I want you to use Super A because
it gets more information. All right.
From now on, use Super A. Josh Ox.
Good Brazilian baddies. Yeah, everybody
wants me to go to Brazilian, right?
Jock.
There you go.
Joe,
good.
Charles
Wuang. I like it. I'll take it.
There you go. Elite 8. Okay, good. Now,
let's go ahead. Let's go back to what
Langy Boy was having. I think Langy Boy
was having it. We need to go back and we
need to create another subnet. Okay, so
we create another subnet. Let's do this
real quick.
We want to put another subnet into Elite
8. What we do here is first at the top
say VPC
VPC networks.
Click on come. Right now I have three
VPCs. Now remember your default VPC.
Don't mess with that. Leave that alone.
Do not touch it. I have birthday VPC
from yesterday and I have Elite 8 VPC
from today. I'm going to go ahead and
use Elite 8. Okay.
Now, here go to subnets and I need to
add a subnet.
Okay.
Before I add the subnet, I need to think
about what subnet am I going to add. So,
I'm going to go back over here in my
paper.
Okay. H what subnet should I do today?
So, let's do
uh Is there Netherlands? Do they got one
in the Netherlands?
Do they have one in the Netherlands?
What do they do?
Madrid? I haven't put anything in over
there yet. So, Netherlands, they do.
Okay, so Netherlands
Netherlands and going to call this one 1
92.168
dot oh that's good
what what number 53
53.0224
Okay. So that's my subnet. Again, you
should always on a piece of paper plan
out your subnets first before you do any
configuration.
So then take this subnet,
copy it.
Okay. So name of my subnets Netherlands
descriptions
another
call this cosmic
techno
underground party.
My region is going to be Netherlands.
There we go. So VPC network is Elite 8.
Okay. And the purpose what the heck is
this?
I don't have to do I'm not going to do
anything with that. IP stack is there
and range. I'm going copy my range.
There it is. All right. private Google
access on.
All right. And going to go ahead and add
it. Should be easy.
We've now added another subnet.
Does anybody have a question regarding
subnets? How to add a subnet?
Oh. Oh, Vincent, this sub this subnet
isn't going away. I just want you to
know. So, I'm going to delete the other
subnetss, but Elite 8 and Vincent Leiso
Booty subnet is going to stay here for
every class. I'm just saying every one
of those is there. I don't know why
though. I can't figure out why, but it's
gonna stay. All right.
All right. So, I want to go ahead and
create an instance.
Okay. So, create instance. We'll go over
here.
Call this one Netherlands
rave.
I'm going to put this into another lens.
Okay. Go down.
Data protection. No backup. Networking.
Allow HTTP traffic first. What? Next.
Network interface.
Network default. Change that to Elite 8.
Automatically goes to Netherlands. Okay.
See how it went? Subnet is automatically
determined. So nice. Go to advanced. I
need my starter script. Guys, startup
script. Use super a.sh.
Use this one. Super a.sh.
Copy this one because it gives me the
information that I need.
Okay. Go back.
Paste. Okay.
Scroll down.
Okay.
And
okay, hold on.
Can I have a little fun here?
No, I can't. Can I
do that?
Okay.
Good.
So,
What is the name of my third VM?
>> Netherlands rave.
>> Good. In which region is it?
>> Netherlands.
>> Good. What is the internal IP of it?
>> 192.168532.
>> Good. There you go. So to make sure that
it works, click here SSH.
Uh we're using Mumbai because it's a
perfect place for Vincent and Liso to
have their honeymoon.
That's why the subnet is 168 192 168.69
because they want to get busy.
Oh, it's going to be curry flavored,
just so you know. Okay, support 22.
Okay,
I say like Theo, you have no chill.
You have no mercy.
Look at
Oh god. See this one? Okay. instance.
Sorry.
No,
I don't think it's funny.
Okay. Right.
So region is Europe West 4 with the
Netherlands.
Your zone is Europe West 4C or you can
just say C. All right. And then you have
instance name Netherlands rave. Okay. So
let's see what you guys got. Vincent,
what you got?
There you go. Class. There you go. Very
good. Vincent's trying to get on my good
side. Just just so you know, Vincent,
you're gonna be my learn teachers aid
every class for a while.
Ted,
there you go. I like it. Very good.
Very good. Malaga, I like that.
Very good. Ernst
Joe,
very good. Berlin Wall, I like it.
Europe, West 10. Very good, Mr. Alex.
Let's see what you got.
There you go.
William Gaval.
Very good. Okay. Good.
Kevin Wilcox.
Very good.
Charles Keys.
Got Wuen.
Good. Hold on. Uhoh. Your your VPC is
default. You didn't put it into the
correct VPC. Sorry, bro.
Yep. Aaron had good eye there.
Alexander Felder.
So, Aussie County, Europe, West One,
Cousins of Vader. I like it. I like it.
Alexander Felder. Very good.
There we go. I like it.
Mr. K.
Okay. Oh, yes. There we go. Plumbing.
Plumbing Fridays. I like that. Love
Kisha. There we go. Mr. K. I like it. I
like what I see. Jacques.
Saturday. There we go. There we go. Very
good.
All right. I like what I see so far. You
guys are figuring it out. Very good.
This is helpful. I like it.
Do you have any questions?
No. You want to see how you delete a
subnet, right?
Okay. So, delete a subnet.
First thing we're going to do, let's
look at the resources real quick. So, I
got Sa Paulo
and No. Okay. So, I can delete Iowa.
So, I'm going to go to Iowa right here.
Oh, sorry. Here it is. US Central One,
which is a lot. I'm not going to do that
one. Tokyo. No, I'm not doing that.
H Tokyo. Delete Tokyo. Okay. Delete
Tokyo. So, it goes here. says delete.
There you go.
And if you want to add a submit,
come over here.
Okay.
Oh, I think
138 138, right? Well, that would be a
good one. Yeah, 138 slash 24.
Okay.
So, I'm going to copy this.
And to add a subnet
name,
remember it can't be can't have
capitals.
Okay. And the region is going to be
where's a good romantic region for that?
Where did I put them?
Where's a good place?
Bangkok.
Oh, I just added to that. They're going
to Bangkok.
All right. So, your IP rate
is 138 because it's 269.
Okay.
Okay. So, paste. Oh, I'm going to hell.
Okay. Anyway.
Yeah, that works. Oh, I need to put a
dot zero there. There we go.
Oh, sorry.
Eight.
Screw that one up. Hold on. 168
zero. Okay. and private Google access.
Yes.
On click off. Okay. And add.
Okay.
Oh sh.
So this is
okay.
So I'm gonna add my I'm going to go
ahead and make a VM. So go create
instance.
I call this Vincent Hollywood.
Okay. And the reason
I got up in Bangkok,
I'm so mad. But okay, it doesn't have
E2.
Some forms are reliable. Oh, [ __ ]
It still be there. Okay, let's put it N.
It's given N2. Good
ta
us. No, I don't want that. I want this
one.
Well, which one is available in Bangkok?
C4.
Oh, that's a big one. Okay, that'll
work. Well, diesel style. Okay. Yeah,
that's a big one. Okay. Um,
data protection, no backups. Networking
allow HTTP traffic, the same thing.
Network interface
elite 8 automatically goes to Lincent
Leisel honeymoon.
It has 269s and it's in Bangkok.
Put the script in there. Oh, where do my
scripts go? Oh, I just erased it, didn't
I? Okay. Uh,
github.com
uh AI.
There we go.
There's tier one
weekly lessons.
Okay. user script. Oh, not that one
script. And
okay, copy it.
Here
I go. And
great.
I should give you an hour of therapy for
free, man.
Oh god, that felt good. Okay, it's still
spinning. It's going to take a while.
All right.
Oh,
current limit. So, there's a limit.
So, we're having a problem with You're
lucky. Bangkok is having a problem.
with the amount that can be spun up
there. So, you're lucky.
Oh god, it's so You're so good. Anyway,
you guys are good sports. Um, go ahead
and knock out
we're going to go ahead and knock out
the uh VMs. So, I knock out this VM
first. So, Sa Paul Apollo 2 and
Netherlands Rave, knock them out.
Delete. Yes. Delete.
Okay.
And this one. So I had a problem.
Dismiss it.
Get rid of that one.
Just tell it. Hey, like just don't don't
do anything. All right.
To tell you the truth, the V the VPC
that you made should be minimal. Well,
that's odd.
Oh. Oh, look at that. You're you're one
of the one of them got erased. Okay,
you're lucky. All right, so all the VMs
are out. Now, if you want to erase your
VPC
and go to your VPC networks over here
and then you just go ahead and choose
which one you want to erase. Do not do
not do not erase default. Okay? Don't do
that. Don't be crazy. Okay? So, if you
go to your subnets and if you want to
erase the subnet, you can in here,
right? I'm going to keep these subnets
because these are useful. Also, I'll
probably use some for teaching next few
weeks.
Okay.
Anyway, uh any questions?
We got Charles.
Good.
Jason,
>> one question I did have is what would
cause the script to not work if the VM
is running?
>> It could be it's who knows just make
sure that the script is copied
correctly.
>> Okay.
>> Um this the normal thing for code is it
for various reasons it for this reason
or another reason it doesn't work. So, I
have to go redo it. It's a part of life.
Just take it on the chin and keep on
going,
>> right?
>> I would say most likely either you
didn't you haven't waited long enough or
I mean you sometimes bootstrapping
fails, but if it's a if it's a known
good script, that's really unlikely,
especially if you're using the same
instance type we are. But, uh
>> yeah,
>> you could try restarting it. I copied it
directly from um Theo's code with the
copy icon
>> and are you certain it's the script
that's failed?
>> I would think so. I mean the VM is
running. I can open it um with SSH.
But like if I paste it in the URL,
>> what's the IP? What's the IP address?
Put it in the chat.
>> Okay, putting it in the chat now. One
sec.
Let me just scan the ports real quick.
Okay.
Spelled commands right.
It's going to make me type it today.
That's okay.
215.
Uh, that's a port. That's a port 80.
Make sure you have port 80 open.
>> All right.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. That's a port.
>> Would that change be on the VPC?
>> Yeah, you have to go directly to the
instance on the VM.
Hey, I got
looks like I made it through the
firewall rule.
Let's see because I I got exit seven on
curl.
So, failed to connect.
Yeah.
So,
well, if the lab's done, I mean, you
could share your screen.
>> Yeah.
>> All right.
>> Wait, where do I I share screen? What
the heck?
Where? Oh, God.
>> Well, there it is.
>> Okay. Sharing now. One second.
>> So in um one tab I've got my VMs.
>> No, no, no. Go back. Go back to the
problematic VM.
>> Yeah. Same for both of them.
>> Reporting.
We'll open one of them
because at least on my side it looks
like uh port 80 is open. No. So click on
the VM. So you see the name, click on
it. It's going to open the instance
details.
>> So start scrolling down. Go to the
networking section.
So HTTP is open. So scroll down all the
way to the bottom.
Okay, drop that menu down for the
startup script at the very bottom. Yep.
Let go all the way to the bottom
and then go all the way to the top of
the startup script. Don't scroll like
just this section here. Yeah.
>> Okay.
And
>> yeah, it hurts.
>> This is super
A that he's using. Is that what you're
using? Super A.
Super A.
>> Hold on.
>> That's not That's not That's Yeah,
that's not right.
>> Hold on. When you made the subnet, did
you allow private access for Google?
>> No, it's the script. It's The script is
wrong.
>> The script is wrong.
>> Yeah.
>> Where? Well, it doesn't say thanks for
Aaron, which means it's not the update
uh updated.
>> It's not the updated one. Yep.
>> That was a
>> because because port 80 is open. You can
you scan the ports and it it makes it
through the firewall. It's just uh
there's nothing listening on port 80 at
that address.
So for the script, I copied it directly
from here.
>> Is this a forked? That's a forked
though.
>> So it's outdated then.
>> So scroll up.
>> Click there.
And then
you see right here
says it's it's behind
Got it. Okay.
>> Click sync fork.
>> Now you'll have a good script.
>> And this is the one that I should be
using instead then. Okay.
>> Yeah. You see? Yeah. It's the one
that'll have the comment that because it
was broken.
>> Okay. All right. I'll retry it with
that. Thank you.
>> Yep.
So, make sure startup scripts are only
uh executed when you first make a VM.
So, you're going to have to just remake
it. Don't try to like edit the settings.
>> Okay, I'll do that now.
>> Yeah, good job.
All right. And then Langy boy,
yours is not working.
Yeah, yours isn't working. Ling boy. Um,
well, we spend a little bit of time
troubleshooting yours. Langing boy, show
your screen because yours is not
working. You got to figure out why.
>> All right. All right.
>> Let's see what you're doing with the
script.
What is it?
Go to networking.
Keep going. Scroll down. Scroll down.
Networking. Networking.
Come on. Stop.
Yeah. Okay, that one's on. Go to your
script. Same thing.
Are you using super a
>> scroll down? Go. No. No. Where did you
go? Stop. Where? Where? Stay there on
that screen.
>> Scroll down.
Keep on going. Scroll. More. More. More.
More. Okay. Now, startup script. Go to
the bottom. You have a that drop down.
Click on
>> No, no, not that one. It says startup
script.
>> I need you to open up
>> right there.
>> There you go.
>> Oh, interesting.
>> If he didn't allow private access when
he made the sub.
>> What's his What's his IP address? Let's
Well, let's I can narrow this down.
Oh, I see it. Is this the one the the
49.4242?
>> I think so. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Give me one second here.
Well,
that's an HTTPS.
Wait, did he try HTTP?
Oh, cuz I mean the comments.
>> Oh, there it is. HTTPS. Yeah, it's HTTP,
bro.
That's why.
>> Okay.
So
>> you put put it correctly. Go to your
URL. We copy the IP address and then use
HTTP not HTTPS.
>> Okay.
Good.
Good job, man.
That URL into the chat and you're you're
good. You can check it.
>> All right.
Is there anybody else in here that
hasn't been able to get this working?
I can hang around for a couple minutes
if Theo has to go as well. Be a good
time.
>> I don't think we'll yet sometime.
Trying to think what I'm going to have
for lunch.
>> Isn't it 5?
>> Uh, yeah. But I didn't eat breakfast
until like
what was it 1?
I think that's a great idea. A various
No.
What I say? No. Waffle House.
Actually,
it kind of is Lavarius, but not there.
The I gota admit like the Latinas here
in the restaurants, they can make some
mean pancakes.
Then they're good. So yeah, if I want to
have a grand slam, I just go to Latinas,
go get it from them.
I sit there and uh study music theory
while I do that.
Anyway,
yep. Enjoy the speed ups, guys. I think
this is out for class, guys. You like I
said, good job. Remember your homework.
Homework is in the in the um repo. And I
hope to God the Ali win. So, let's hope
this let's hope let's hope it goes well.
Um,
tip off is a little bit. Go have a good
day. Okay, guys. I will see you next
week. Good job. And remember the subnet,
our favorite subnetss. We're going to
have this subnet next week. We're use
the same one. I'll talk to you later.
Byebye.